<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[TechWaifu's RSS Feed of the best technology and computer science blogs]]></title><description><![CDATA[TechWaifu's RSS Feed of the best technology and computer science blogs]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 03:20:31 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Retrospect: Choosing The Perfect College Major]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you find yourself stuck in choosing what college degree to pursue, then don’t worry, you are not alone. Many of us do not know what we…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/choosing-college-major-688412f1</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/choosing-college-major-688412f1</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself stuck in choosing what college degree to pursue, then don’t worry, you are not alone. Many of us do not know what we want to do with our lives until many years later, hence why many adults experience a quarter-life and mid-life crisis quite often. As you find yourself deciding what career path to pursue, let me share with you my thoughts from what I’ve experienced in college and my lessons that may or may not help you in the long run. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many young students are left with two options to choose from: a career with good money and stability vs. a career that relates to their interests and hobbies. Between these two choices, one will usually mean accepting what society tells them is successful, while the other one means turning their backs on what they love doing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common outcome is picking a college degree that will provide good pay and stability. A reason for this is because money and economic profits is the number one motivation above all else. We create normality out of any practice or profession and we put labels on what majors have higher chance of success. Over the years, we have started to abuse this concept by narrowing our options and only strive for high paying jobs only. We neglect what other options are there that might fit our personality and our stress levels better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, as a society, have mixed inner greatness with money and power and place influence on each generation that comes along. No one dares to explore other professions as much because everyone wants to make their money proliferate in this affluent type of culture rather than spending their time doing something they love. That is because the words “money” and “success” are akin in most people’s minds and are something constant no matter who or where we came from. Students who do decide to major in music, philosophy, or liberal arts often face severe feelings of inadequacy because they are compared to society’s standard of what is successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most college students are afraid to choose the major they love because their major is not a profession that the parents approve of necessarily, or that society necessarily approves of. While some students pick stressful majors because they love “engineering” or because they have a “passion” for science, I can’t help wondering why they would dive in a tremendous amount of anxiety and unhappiness for the sake of material gain and reputation. However, it’s not the student’s fault. Parents, a lot of the time, tells us to shade our own legacy conforming to what society tells us is right. I learned that there is a huge space of contradiction as we grow up. Often parents tell us to be what we want to be, except ourselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But our legacy is what we create of it, and it is so much easier to craft legacy for ourselves with something we know we are good at. But sometimes what we are good at isn’t enough to survive in the real world. But, it is so much easier and enjoyable to be good at something when we are passionate about something, and if we’re passionate about something, we’re happy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let it be repeated that a student’s college major is not a role they play in society. It does not constitute a real picture of success; it is merely the conventional appearance of excessive pressure from today’s standards of greatness. These fields that we pursue, these jobs that we end up picking for ourselves, should be ones that we’re comfortable with and love to do. Not necessarily comfortable, it might be very uncomfortable to say the least, but pick something that you love and have passion for. And even though it might be intimidating, thrust yourself into it anyway, not because society or your parents tell us, but because you want to.
&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Importance of Code Quality and the Impact of Technical Debt]]></title><description><![CDATA[It was my first day on the job and I had totaled eight hours of chugging coffee, banging my head at the keyboard for the fifth time, and…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/importance-of-code-quality-impact-of-tech-debt-1fb19358</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/importance-of-code-quality-impact-of-tech-debt-1fb19358</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It was my first day on the job and I had totaled eight hours of chugging coffee, banging my head at the keyboard for the fifth time, and fighting the desire to rewrite the entire codebase. According to my calculations, that&apos;s zero hours of productivity. At the beginning of my career I didn&apos;t care too much about code quality. As long as the code compiled and worked why did it matter right? Back in college, I was always pressed for time trying to finish programming assignments from four different Upper Div Computer Science courses. The programming assignments lasted at most a week or two and then we started a new project from scratch the next week. Hence, I never learned the importance of writing maintainable code. I kept this mentality with me to my first job and learned the hard way how difficult it becomes to add new features on top of bad quality code. The term for this is called technical debt or tech debt for short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wherefore Art Thou Tech Debt?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s describe the different ways tech debt can form. The most common form of tech debt comes from the backlog of bugs and hacks that have piled up in the codebase and nobody wants to fix. Other less obvious forms of tech debt include lack of tests, use of legacy frameworks and libraries, or a lack of thorough code reviews. I see this most common when teams have a tight deadline requiring teams to churn out code without maintaining good code. I also see this when the engineering teams are forced to start implementation without a clear set of requirements or UX mocks. Tech debt can also accrue from bad design due to lack of guidance from more senior engineer. In fact, you can design a great system at the time, but it may not age well over time due influences outside your control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there&apos;s a constant push and pull relationship between the business needs and engineering standards. This kind of debt is not the same as how businesses can take on debt to expand their business. For example, a pizza business can take on debt to expand their operations in hopes of bringing in more revenue in the future. Tech debt has an inverse effect where adding new features can decrease code quality. Let&apos;s imagine you have a button with square corners, but the UX team wants a new rounded corners button for just one page. While adding a new button with different styling doesn&apos;t sound like that much work to finish, you&apos;ve just doubled the number of buttons you need to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sounds Bad But If the Product Works, Why Should I Care?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s think back to that time you had to implement that hack you said you would fix later, but 3 months later you&apos;re hit with a bug that takes a week to fix. What about that time you wrote some incomplete code, but didn&apos;t leave some comments? Or what about that time you made a brand new util class instead of refactoring an existing class that did something similar? These are all small steps towards accruing tech debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&apos;s look at a more severe case when all that unmanaged tech debt has come back to haunt you. The PM (Product Manager) comes asking you to implement that new shiny feature. You start coding away, but realize how difficult it is to implement this feature without adding more hacks on top of existing hacks. However, you succeed at implementation the new feature within a week. A week later you come back to the same codebase and you have no idea what you wrote. Ok whatever right? A new sprint cycle starts and your PM comes back with another feature request and you start churning code, but this time it takes you two weeks to implement this feature due to how complex the codebase has become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR: Unmanaged tech debt can lead up to a point where it becomes impossible to add new feature, extend deadlines beyond control, or demotivate engineers to touch that code. It can also make it easier to introduce unexpected bugs since the codebase becomes more brittle and fragile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How can we tell when too much tech debt has incurred?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech debt is impossible to avoid, but there are definitely ways to mitigate it as long as you recognize detect it. Let&apos;s look at some obvious signals of incurring tech debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too many parts of the code that have been copy pasted, but can be shared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unclear code or lack of comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The existing codebase has grown in an unexpected manner making it harder to make new features &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code becomes more tedious to test via unit/integration tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too many TODOs and HACKs in the code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower velocity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last two points can be tracked with tools such as Jira or some other project management tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Too many TODOs and HACKs in the code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good practice to track TODOs, bugs, and hacks is to create a tracker for each item and add a comment in your code so others can easily check the bug. I like to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;// TODO(issues/1#issue-670532172): Remove the name param once we support id to name conversion.
function doThing(id, name) {} 

// HACK(issues/1#issue-670532172): Setting document.window so we can work around blah blah.
document.window = windowWorkAround();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes it much more apparent which parts of the code are using a hack or needs to be updated in the future. Anyone reading the code can easily lookup the tracker and read the tracker for more context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were many times I told myself I would go back and fix that bug, but forgot about it a week later. So having a solid record makes it easier for you and other team members to see what&apos;s going on. Leaving a record is also important when people leave the team. Not everyone stays in the same team or company their entire career, so it&apos;s best to leave some context for that poor soul who will have to handle that bug when the original author has left. But in practice, people don&apos;t usually go back and fix bugs even if there is a paper trail. A good way to approach the backlog of bugs is to incite your team to have bug bash sessions which we&apos;ll talk about later in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lower Velocity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s first talk about what is velocity. Velocity is a measure of how fast a team can deliver a requirement. Velocity can be calculated by how quickly the team can complete tasks during a sprint which are usually weekly or biweekly. These tasks are also paired with an estimated time or complexity to weight the task appropriately. The velocity of the team can be used to determine how much work a team can take on for that specific sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech debt can impact velocity and usually in a negative manner. Usually it can make the estimates higher than it should be since features might be harder to fix or refactoring is required. Sometimes tasks are underestimated and end up taking much longer to complete due to the required refactoring or the extra hack. Other times it can cause the team to want to avoid taking on ownership of a specific task due to how difficult it is to address. All in all, unaddressed tech debt can and will extend development time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to manage tech debt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my career, I&apos;ve seen teams approach tech debt in many different ways. I&apos;ve compiled a list of some of the methods to do so, but I think the first step to take is having a culture change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changing Team Culture Regarding Code Quality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a junior Software Engineer, I wasn&apos;t aware of the implications of tech debt until I attended a Code Health conference. I&apos;m now a firm believer that team awareness on this topic is critical in order to change the team&apos;s mentality towards tech debt. Most developers would rather create brand new features than fix some bug. Who doesn&apos;t right? New features are usually the most existing things to add and create impact. This is why it&apos;s important to have a good team culture regarding fixing bugs. The team should weigh those bug fixes just as important as anything else because it impacts the overall team indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If Something is Broken, Fix It&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your house has a broken window, would you leave it broken or would you fix it? You can take the easy route and ignore the window, but this can lead to more troubles later. What if it rains or snows? You can also just board up the window with some wood, or you can spend some quality time and properly fix it. You can view tech debt in the same manner. Sometimes the best way to manage tech debt is to go out of your way to fix it. Take the initiative even if its not within scope or if it will be rewarded because your team your appreciate your efforts. You can read more on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/the-broken-window-theory/&quot;&gt;broken window theory here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Having a Rotational On-duty Person&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my team, we have a weekly on-duty rotation where the on-duty person stops working on their features for the week to focus on the backlog or fixing broken integration tests. This will ensure tech debt is never neglected since someone will always been looking into it. This is also a great way for new members to onboard and learn about the whole system since they can work on parts of the code no one usually touches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pushing Back On Feature Requests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the best way to balance tech debt is to work with PMs and UX on compromise. If they ask for a certain feature that requires a hack try to work with them on alternate solutions so all parties can be happy. It is also important to communicate how long features may take due to required refactoring. I don&apos;t think we should say no completely, but having a compromise on both ends maintains a healthy balance between new features and tech debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recurring Bug Bashes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Push management to dedicate time to handle tech debt because often times, companies don&apos;t. Maybe dedicate one sprint cycle during a holiday season when there isn&apos;t much work to do. My team does is a yearly bug bash where we stop working on features and focus on any lingering bugs, hacks, or infrastructure improvements for a week. To make it fun, we track the number of bugs fixed and reward the top contributor a small prize. Don&apos;t ignore all your tech debt until these bug bashes occur though! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Migrating Pieces of Legacy Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve noticed tech debt incurs in both new and legacy codebases. However, legacy codebases are plagued by old frameworks, libraries, programming languages, and old coding conventions. Sometimes the best way to tackle this is by slowly migrating those pieces of code. If you&apos;re dealing with a monolithic server, consider breaking it up into micro services piece by piece. If you&apos;re a frontend developer using an old framework, look into building new components in a new framework. You don&apos;t always have to be locked down to your current tech stack just because the it&apos;s been that way for ages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Convincing Management with Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team spent the last 4 years rewriting the entire product from scratch to abandon the decade old tech stack it was written on. Four years is a long time to spend rewriting an entire tech stack and halting any feature development, so how did we get approval? It&apos;s important to quantify and communicate to leadership the benefits and expected outcomes from handling tech debt. Some good metrics to communicate can include faster release times, a more comprehensible codebase, faster development times, how much money can be saved in the long run, and feasibility for new features. Having charts or tools to visual the outcomes is also useful for non-technical people. For example, our team switched our tech stack that supported server-side rendering and better caching which improved initial load time. We convinced leadership that this feature was worth pursuing since studies have shown &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/marketing-resources/data-measurement/mobile-page-speed-new-industry-benchmarks/&quot;&gt;decreasing page load time can increase conversions&lt;/a&gt;. You don&apos;t need to completely start over like my team, but leadership needs to convinced there is some sort of positive impact towards the business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has tech debt plagued you in the past? What did your team do to approach it? Did you enjoy this article? If so, check out this article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/difference-between-studying-computer-science-working-software-engineer-df3bb680&quot;&gt;https://techwaifu.com/difference-between-studying-computer-science-working-software-engineer-df3bb680&lt;/a&gt; and don&apos;t forget to leave a comment in the comments section below!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Programming in School vs Working as a Software Engineer]]></title><description><![CDATA[While I started studying Computer Science, I always wondered if working in the real world would be as difficult as college. I struggled to…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/difference-between-studying-computer-science-working-software-engineer-df3bb680</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/difference-between-studying-computer-science-working-software-engineer-df3bb680</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;While I started studying Computer Science, I always wondered if working in the real world would be as difficult as college. I struggled to learn a lot of the theories and constantly wondered why I had to take most of these courses. It turns out the real world is much different from school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Academia Side of Computer Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While studying computer science at a university, professors will generally teach you about the science of programming. Hence you&apos;ll take a lot of theory and math courses to understand the fundamentals of how programming works behind the scenes. A typical university curriculum may include some of the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Structures and Analysis of Algorithms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theory of Computation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fundamental Concepts of Languages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compilers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Organization, Systems Programming, and Computer Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probability and Statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, the assignments are well defined problems with known solutions. These assignments are meant to be solved within a well defined time span. It is very unlikely that undergraduates will be given assignments with unclear requirements since these courses are meant to help you learn a specific Computer Science topic. All in all, getting a degree in Computer Science will teach you how to write and debug basic code and how apply the theories taught in lecture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What it&apos;s like working in the workforce as a Computer Engineer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, most university curriculums don&apos;t prepare students how to operate in a real work environment. A common misconception is that Software Engineers just sit at their desks chugging coffee and coding all day. However, this is far from reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writing code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All entry level Software Engineers spend 80% of their time writing code. The other 20% revolve around going to meetings and attending scrum. Generally, PMs and a Techlead plan out the deliverables that have already been scoped out. These deliverables are small enough for any engineer to code out. Sometimes the Techlead will also provide a design doc when the implementation portion is unclear for entry level Software Engineers. Most of the smaller tasks have predefined requirements by the PMs and Techlead. Software Engineers need to digest the requirements and transform it into code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One big difference between writing code at a university and in the real world is that most university courses don&apos;t focus on how to code in a large codebase. In the real world, you&apos;ll rarely get to start on a fresh codebase or a get skeleton that&apos;s provided by someone else. Also in the real world, most projects can take months to complete unlike university assignments which span a week to complete. However, when you start in the industry you&apos;ll notice one similarity, the requirements are all flushed out. Both university assignments and entry level tasks have clear requirements that have already been defined by someone else. You&apos;ll see as you grow in your career, this starts to change very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Designing Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s important to note that in the workplace, you&apos;ll be creating products and solving real problems for real people. Hence, a lot more thought goes into designing the system as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you advance in your career, you&apos;ll start to write less code and start to design larger systems. When I started my career, my tech leads would give me a design doc to implement. As I advanced in my career, I started to design systems with much larger scope that were meant for multiple engineers to work on. Part of this includes analyzing requirements and understanding what is technically feasible in a given timeframe. This also requires you to have a solid technical background in order to figure out what frameworks or solutions to apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&apos;ll rarely use those advanced concepts taught in school. Most of the time you&apos;ll be using APIs of other frameworks or libraries. In 95% of my projects, I had to learn about other systems or frameworks and figure out how to piece them together to create something new. For example, when I made a web app, I had to learn how to use React and someone else&apos;s calendar Widget. I had to figure out how to piece their calendar widget with my React form and the best way to propagate data back and forth. However, knowing those concepts are important when applying those frameworks to your code. Being able to recognize using a certain function can turn your runtime from O(n^2) to O(n) is extremely valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of my courses taught me the importance of designing the system before starting to write code. In my courses, as long as my code compiled and passed the tests it was good to go. There was never a reason to design more than one working solution. In my current workplace, I have multiple options each listed with pros and cons. I have thoughtful discussions with other engineers on the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real world problems are often complex and blurry. Requirements can change overtime. You&apos;re often designing systems that can be replaced or refactored in the future. This is because in the real world, you&apos;re focused on designing solutions for real people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Testing the system and maintaining upkeep of that system&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed a lot of Software Engineers entering this field don&apos;t learn the importance of testing until they start working. Often, universities provide a test suite that the students can run against to verify their solution is working. In a production codebase, you&apos;ll have to check in tests with the code. Depending on the feature, it could be an integration test, unit test, or a visual test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the real world, you&apos;ll also have to maintain that test and the system. I learned that tests can be flaky time to time. Things like Webdriver tests aren&apos;t perfect and sometimes you&apos;ll need to revisit your existing tests to make them stable again. Production code is used by real people, so it&apos;s detrimental if your system crashes and goes down. Unlike a college assignment, you&apos;ll need to invest time into logging, capturing metrics, and scaling the system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Collaborating with PMs, UX, Stakeholders, and other Software Engineers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to common belief, Software Engineers are not locked up in their code coding in the dark and hiding from humanity. In reality Software Engineers have to collaborate with Product Managers, UX Designers, Stakeholders, and other Engineers. PMs have a good idea of the problem that needs to get solved. UX Designers know how to create beautiful mocks and understand human interaction principals. Software Engineers know how to take both the requirements and mocks and turn them into working code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed it&apos;s a constant tug of war between adding new requirements and balancing tech debt. Sometimes PM or UX requirements have challenging implications such as increased tech debt or the solution may take too long to complete in the given time frame. It&apos;s up to the Software Engineers to flag this and work with the respective parties to come to a balanced solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Estimating the time and effort required to build out a system in a given timeframe&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing Software Engineers have to do is estimate how long it will take to complete a project. Leadership takes these estimates in order to figure out how to sequence things. Figuring out how difficult and how long a project can is also a good trait to learn. In school, you&apos;re generally bound to a fixed deadline, but in the real workplace, deadlines are more flexible since they&apos;re set based on the amount of work required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, university curriculums teach students how computers interpret programming languages and how to utilize different data structures and algorithms, but it&apos;s different from how things are in the industry. In the industry, you&apos;ll be expected to design real systems for real people. Projects will take much longer to complete due to the larger scope. However, university curriculums help provide the fundamentals required in the work place. If this article was interesting, take a look on &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/how-i-got-multiple-fang-offers-e0a87898&quot;&gt;how I Landed Offers from Facebook, Google, Uber, &amp;#x26; Microsoft as a Software Engineer&lt;/a&gt;. Did you get a Computer Science degree? Do you think it was useful? Let me know in the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is the Leica CL still worth $3000 in 2020?]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Leica CL (not to be confused with the 1973 Leica CL) is an APS-C camera that was released in 2017. It uses the L-mount which features…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/leica-cl-worth-3000-in-2020-9cbf32a8</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/leica-cl-worth-3000-in-2020-9cbf32a8</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The Leica CL (not to be confused with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leica_CL&quot;&gt;1973 Leica CL&lt;/a&gt;) is an APS-C camera that was released in 2017. It uses the L-mount which features autofocus unlike the conventional M-mount that most Leica cameras use. I&apos;ve had many people ask me if the Leica CL is worth it in 2020, so let&apos;s take a look at how well it fairs in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Specs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specs&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Max resolution&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6,000×4,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Effective pixels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;24 megapixels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sensor size&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;APS-C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sensor type&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CMOS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ISO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-50000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Max shutter speed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/25000 sec - 30 sec&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Weight with battery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;483g (1.06lb)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dimensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;131 x 78 x 45 mm (5.2 x 3.1 x 1.8&quot;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Year Released&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Build&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Leica CL has a very elegant and classic Leica look. The camera is smaller and lighter than your typical mirrorless camera at 483g (1.06lb) which makes it the ideal travel camera. While the camera is light, the camera is extremely durable. The body is made of magnesium and top and bottom plates are black anodized aluminum. The body is also wrapped in fine-grain leather. It also comes with the trademark Leica logo on the front. Design-wise, the CL is basically a mini Leica M.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/32UMMwv&quot;&gt;Leica TL2&lt;/a&gt; and the Leica CL share the same sensor, but have a different body. I personally prefer the look and feel of the CL over the TL2. The TL2 doesn&apos;t come with an EVF which is a biggie for me and the leather wrapping just feels nicer to hold. However, I do wish the CL came with a grip like the TL2 to make the camera easier to hold. You can purchase an optional &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2WZP61x&quot;&gt;Leica CL Handgrip&lt;/a&gt;, but it&apos;s pretty expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Autofocus&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most Leica cameras, this comes with autofocus like the SL, Q, and other T series making it easier for newcomers to pick up and use. This camera comes with a 49 point contract-detect autofocus system. It works pretty good for a camera that came out in 2017, but I found Sony&apos;s autofocus to be far superior. I found the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2D76Zod&quot;&gt;Sony RX100vii&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s eye detection to blow the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/302h1A2&quot;&gt;Leica CL&lt;/a&gt; out of the water. The camera supports shooting at up to 10 frames per second. Don&apos;t expect to use this for sports photography, but it&apos;s definitely not a slow camera. Thankfully, you can also use your M lens with this camera if you pick up a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3g1Ql82&quot;&gt;M-Adapter T&lt;/a&gt;. These lens will only work in manual focus, but it&apos;s a nice option you have M lens sitting around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Controls&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/lDZBsPgh.jpg?width=1000&amp;#x26;height=730&quot; alt=&quot;Leica CL Controls&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Leica is unique since it comes with 2 unlabeled wheels which have different functionality based on your shooting mode. I found it difficult to remember what each dial does since it&apos;s not labeled, so I ended up just sticking to Aperture Priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s also a monochrome LCD that shows your shooting mode, aperture, shutter speed, ISO, and exposure compensation. I honestly don&apos;t use it too often since that information is available through the viewfinder. The viewfinder is a welcome addition since the TL series require the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OVfhSP&quot;&gt;Visoflex to use a EVF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera doesn&apos;t have that many buttons in general. On the back there&apos;s a Play, Function, and Menu button. The dials can also be down on to change certain settings depending on your mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4K video at up to 30 frames per second&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera supports shooting video at 4k, but I haven&apos;t recorded any videos on it so I won&apos;t comment on the quality of the videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Transfer Over Wifi&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera also comes with the ability to transfer photos over WIFI using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/leica-fotos/id1356061526&quot;&gt;Leica Fotos app&lt;/a&gt;. I found this too painful to use since it took a long time to transfer the RAW files. I recommend sticking to transferring via the memory card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Leica CL supports shooting in both RAW (DNG) and JPEG. The RAW files are pretty large at around 45MB at a resolution of 6,000 x 4,000. The JPEGs are reasonably smaller at around 10MB per photo. The camera only sports one UHS SD card slot, so be prepared to buy a big SD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3g5PSBG&quot;&gt;Leica Elmarit TL 18mm lens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Elmarit is an 18mm lens (equivalent to a 27mm lens in the full-frame 35mm format). I initially thought this focal length would be perfect for everyday shooting, but I didn&apos;t spend too much time with this lens since I found the f/2.8 aperture a bit too slow for my liking. There&apos;s a bit of softness in the edges and corner, but the center is really sharp. I do like the small pancake size which makes it easy to take around as a secondary lens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these photos were shot with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3g5PSBG&quot;&gt;Leica Elmarit TL 18mm lens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50156261086_6708bb9d9b_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50156494267_7497d2f623_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50156263331_17d1c21de4_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50155706418_972d8e9ec6_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50155707323_a8dac0b7eb_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50156497722_6394fca7b2_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;Elmarit&quot;&gt;
&lt;/img-carousel&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39r9YUm&quot;&gt;Leica Summilux TL 35mm f/1.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3g5PSBG&quot;&gt;Leica Elmarit TL 18mm lens&lt;/a&gt; had a larger aperture at f/1.4. It&apos;s sometimes hard to capture photos in low light without having to bump up the ISO. I ended up purchasing &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39r9YUm&quot;&gt;Leica Summilux TL 35mm f/1.4&lt;/a&gt; and never looked back. The Summilux is a wonderful lens. It produces creamy and beautiful bokeh that notorious Leica look. I personally think it&apos;s a big step up from the other Leica L lenses. The Summilux is a bit front heavy compared to the Elmarit, but it&apos;s still well built. There&apos;s a bit of chromatic aberrations time to time, but like any lens, that can be fixed in post production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these photos were shot with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39r9YUm&quot;&gt;Leica Summilux TL 35mm f/1.4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153365536_dee6178fad_k.jpg?width=1365&amp;#x26;height=2048&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/1.4 | 1/250 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153364736_bcbd58f99f_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/5.6 | 1/400 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153600887_b94a0ae3fa_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/6.3 | 1/320 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50152812678_5a0c9ec9e6_k.jpg?width=1365&amp;#x26;height=2048&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/3.5 | 1/100 sec | ISO 125&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50152811723_73d83d4957_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/4.0 | 1/160 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50152810228_2de5dda860_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/2.8 | 1/500 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153591717_92e6fd57e4_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/1.4 | 1/3200 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153590842_35ba5bb14b_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/1.6 | 1/1600 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50152804168_d78040749f_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/13 | 1/100 sec | ISO 160&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153351531_900d7b93b5_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/1.8 | 1/1000 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153587332_2a011bac87_k.jpg?width=2048&amp;#x26;height=1365&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Summilux Image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-caption&gt;ƒ/2.5 | 1/800 sec | ISO 100&lt;/img-caption&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Animals&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153580732_3be8ea6c6f_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50152797333_46832e5391_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50156259816_d8ae439be4_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;LeicaCLAnimals&quot;&gt;
&lt;/img-carousel&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Landscapes&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50155697133_361d72d527_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153347591_865b13918a_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153344711_3a5c5b17af_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153348741_df93e6a640_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;LeicaCLLandscapes&quot;&gt;
&lt;/img-carousel&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Bokeh&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50156489522_ab5a388757_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50155698348_796f378044_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153578907_de0c9227b9_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153350701_daa291a98c_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;LeicaCLBokeh&quot;&gt;
&lt;/img-carousel&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Low light Performance&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera&apos;s lowlight performance is decent. I don&apos;t suggest pushing the camera over ISO 6400. I also found the camera struggled a bit in dark situations even at f/1.4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153595417_a1d6a45df1_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153357566_a9797818f4_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50152814688_76eaffe71a_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153593982_b6cc46f0ac_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153593062_38ab01b345_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50153355101_b9ea0a89ff_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;LeicaCLLowLight&quot;&gt;
&lt;/img-carousel&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find all the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/s/aHsmPDfL7U&quot;&gt;images taken from the Leica CL here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Verdict&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When this camera first came out, kit with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3g5PSBG&quot;&gt;Leica Elmarit TL 18mm lens&lt;/a&gt; cost around $4000. I bought this camera back in early 2019 for $3195 which came with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3g5PSBG&quot;&gt;Leica Elmarit TL 18mm f/2.8&lt;/a&gt;. You can get the same &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2D4ypLi&quot;&gt;bundle&lt;/a&gt; in 2020 for $3000. I also bought the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/39r9YUm&quot;&gt;Leica Summilux TL 35mm f/1.4&lt;/a&gt; which cost $2500. In total, I spent $5700 before tax. This is still cheap compared to Leica&apos;s other offerings like the M10 or the SL series, but the real question is it worth it in 2020? It depends. Like all Leica cameras, you can get a full frame camera at the same price with much better specs, a better selection of lens, and faster autofocus. You can pair the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OVO8Pv&quot;&gt;Sony a7R IV&lt;/a&gt; which costs $3200 with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2CQLubf&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 2/25&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OT8bxY&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 85mm&lt;/a&gt; and still be under $5700. If you must buy a Leica, I would recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2D9RrQi&quot;&gt;Leica Q2&lt;/a&gt; over the Leica CL + Summilux in 2020 since it&apos;s about $700 cheaper. Check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/leica-q2-first-impressions-a0297887&quot;&gt;hands on impression of the Leica Q2&lt;/a&gt; to learn more. However, if you demand a light and minimalist camera with interchangeable lens and amazing build quality, then this camera is for you. Even though, it&apos;s an APS-C camera, my Leica CL outperforms my previous Sony a7ii in most situations (maybe not lowlight). The camera lens are also top notch and high quality. I do question whether Leica will continue to produce T series cameras though. I&apos;m hoping Leica will put out a successor to the CL so I can continue to use my TL lens in the future to make my investment worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;review score=&quot;75&quot; data=&quot;{&apos;score&apos;:75,&apos;pros&apos;:[&apos;Light and well built&apos;,&apos;Amazing as a travel camera&apos;,&apos;Cheapest Leica camera with interchangeable lens&apos;,&apos;Supports M lens with an adapter&apos;],&apos;cons&apos;:[&apos;Small selection of L lens&apos;,&apos;Autofocus is not as great as competition in 2020&apos;,&apos;Still expensive even 3 years after initial release&apos;]}&quot;&gt;&lt;/review&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Impact of Burnout]]></title><description><![CDATA[Majority of us have probably felt burned out ever since Covid-19 happened. Unfortunate events have happened where teams have become smaller…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/impact-of-burnout-1673a494</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/impact-of-burnout-1673a494</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Majority of us have probably felt burned out ever since Covid-19 happened. Unfortunate events have happened where teams have become smaller and work has become larger in volume for the rest. In a way, this has led companies to expect their remaining employees to be available 24/7 and take advantage of the situation. Of course, not all companies encourage this practice, but after talking to coworkers and peers, it seems all of us are depressed with the situation that we are stuck with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so grateful and blessed that I still have a job during these uncertain times, but the truth is my room feels like an office. My desk no longer feels like my personal space. I’ve lost my energy to pursue my side projects on the weekend. I don’t have energy to respond to my closest friends. I haven’t enjoyed eating a single meal with my parents. My work-life balance has just been about work and carrying the stress on the weekend. Having this mindset for almost half a year (and my back hurting like shit every day) made me question what’s important to me and if I should set my foot down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my years in my career, I have never been the type of person to tell my manager &quot;no&quot;. I admit that I tend to add more stress on my plate in return for an &quot;Ok, great thanks&quot; email. No matter if you’re Gen Z, Millennial, or a boomer, I find the common reason why we agree to put ourselves into this type of situation is ultimately money and being able to afford stability for ourselves and our family. But, my  question is does it ever get better? No, actually it doesn&apos;t. I learned we only get used to this grind until one day we’re 50 and realize we hate our lives and what we became. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I will leave this post with a positive note. Your perception of who you are does not revolve around how many tasks or emails you can finish  in one day. Do not distort your idea of success with money and temporary stress. Be kinder to yourself because you are doing great and exercise more to help your back problems. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Remote Procedure Calls (RPC) Are Better than REST]]></title><description><![CDATA[Most modern services and clients communicate with REST with JSON as a data interchange format. JSON is easy to read and most programming…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/why-use-remote-procedure-calls-RPC-over-JSON-fbb4ae56</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/why-use-remote-procedure-calls-RPC-over-JSON-fbb4ae56</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Most modern services and clients communicate with REST with JSON as a data interchange format. JSON is easy to read and most programming languages can easily parse JSON. The ease of use comes with its cons though. You can&apos;t enforce a well defined structure and protocol between the client and server. You can send extra data that the recipient doesn&apos;t care about. JSON is also pretty big in terms of size compared to protos. Let&apos;s take a look at protos and how it can solve some of those issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Does a Protobuf look like?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different versions of proto in GRPC, but I&apos;ll be referencing &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/proto&quot;&gt;proto3&lt;/a&gt; which is the newest version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;syntax = &quot;proto3&quot;;

message SearchRequest {
  string query = 1;
  int32 page_number = 2;
  int32 result_per_page = 3;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical proto looks like this. Each field has a type (string), a field name (query), and a unique field number (1). The field number is used to figure out how to encode the field and its location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Protos Establish a Schema&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you saw in the example earlier, the proto defined a schema of a SearchRequest. Having a schema is important because it guarantees type-safety and prevents schema-violations. The best part of protos is that you can have a server implementation in one language and a client in a different language and the proto can be consumed without any difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In GRPC, you can also define services which are like REST endpoints. Let&apos;s expand on the example from above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;syntax = &quot;proto3&quot;;

service SearchService {
  rpc Search (SearchRequest) returns (SearchResponse);
}

message SearchRequest {
  string query = 1;
  int32 page_number = 2;
  int32 result_per_page = 3;
}

message SearchResponse {
  string response = 1;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s say we have a Go server that implements &lt;code&gt;SearchService&lt;/code&gt;. The implementation will look something like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type searchServer struct {}

func (s *searchServer) Search(ctx context.Context, req *pb.SearchRequest) (*pb.SearchResponse, error) {
  // TODO: Implement the Server
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Javascript Client can the server like so&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;const service = new SearchServiceClient(&apos;http://localhost:8080&apos;);

const req = new SearchRequest();
req.setQuery(&quot;AnimalCrossing&quot;);
req.setPageNumber(3);
req.setResultsPerPage(100);

service.search(req, {}, (err, resp) =&gt; {});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An equivalent client in REST would look like so: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;const data = {
    query: &quot;AnimalCrossing&quot;,
  pageNumber: 3,
  resultsPerPage: 100,
};

fetch(&quot;/search&quot;, data);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with the 2nd approach is that you cannot guarentee any type safety or check for required fields without extra business logic. You can also set a field incorrectly like using &lt;code&gt;page_number&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;pageNumber&lt;/code&gt;. I also think the RPC version is much more readable. You can tell exactly what the data is by reading the object name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;REST based APIs do not have schema out of the box. If you want to give your REST API a schema, you&apos;ll need to use something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://json-schema.org/&quot;&gt;JSON Schema&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Network Requests Transmit Less Bytes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s see how SearchRequest might look like in JSON vs proto. Let&apos;s say the client sets query to &quot;animal crossing&quot;, &lt;code&gt;page_number&lt;/code&gt; to 3, and &lt;code&gt;result_per_page&lt;/code&gt; to 100. Once this proto is populated and serialized, it will look something like this &lt;code&gt;[&quot;animal crossing&quot;,3,100]&lt;/code&gt;. In JSON, you&apos;ll represent the same object like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{
    &quot;query&quot;: &quot;animal crossing&quot;,
    &quot;page_number&quot;: 3,
    &quot;result_per_page&quot;: 100
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can already tell the serialized proto version requires less characters to represent than the equivalent in JSON. This is really good for companies that need to shave as much data off each request/response to make network requests as small as possible. The only issue is the serialized proto is not easy for a human being to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Protos Can Be Used In a Plethora of Programming Languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like REST, RPCs and protos can be consumed by any programming language. Here&apos;s some tutorials from Google on how to set up &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/tutorials&quot;&gt;protos&lt;/a&gt;. There are also open source projects to set up protos for other programming languages like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/protobufjs/protobuf.js&quot;&gt;protobuf.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I&apos;m a big fan of how RPCs define a clear and well defined schema and transmits less bytes over the wire. I also think using protos help increase the readability of the code since everything is typed and objects are initialized with the proto object. Have you used RPCs before? Do you prefer that over REST? Let me know in the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Things I wish I knew Before Buying a Tesla Model 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[1. Autopilot is Impressive, but it's Still a Work in Progress I was excited about the concept of just sitting in my car and letting my car…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/things-wish-knew-before-buying-tesla-model-3-91515f9c</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/things-wish-knew-before-buying-tesla-model-3-91515f9c</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;1. Autopilot is Impressive, but it&apos;s Still a Work in Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited about the concept of just sitting in my car and letting my car drive through Bay Area traffic, but we&apos;re still not there yet. You&apos;ll still need to hold onto the steering wheel or else the car will eventually stop. Autopilot is great for in a predictable environment like freeways, but it still can&apos;t drive locally yet. Tesla recently added &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/support/autopilot&quot;&gt;support for detecting stop signs and street lights&lt;/a&gt;, but that requires Full Self-Driving which is an extra $8000 in addition to the base Autopilot package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. The Range is Less than the Advertised Range&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla advertises the Standard Range Plus to have 240 miles of range. In reality, it&apos;s much less. This can also change depending on weather conditions. The car&apos;s battery will drain much faster overnight when it&apos;s out in the cold.
That&apos;s not to say road trips are impossible with Teslas. There are Superchargers all over the US. As of July 2020, there are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/supercharger?redirect=no&quot;&gt;1971 Superchargers Stations&lt;/a&gt;. If you plan on taking the car for a long trip, be prepared to take multiple stops to charge your car at Superchargers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. There&apos;s a Bunch of Awesome Third Party Accessories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla sells a lot of accessories on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.tesla.com/category/vehicle-accessories/model-3&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;, but most of these are pretty expensive. Thankfully, you can find alternative items and accessories you won&apos;t find from Tesla on Amazon. Here&apos;s some of my favorite accessories that I&apos;ve purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://getjeda.com/tesla-model3-usb-hub/&quot;&gt;Jeda USB Hub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://getjeda.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Model 3 USB Hub&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front console only has 2 USB inputs. If you purchased the device before 2020, the car comes with 2 USB A ports, but newer models come with 1 USB A and 1 USB C. I realized really quickly that this wasn&apos;t enough ports especially if you have a wireless charger and you&apos;re using a USB port for Sentry Mode. Luckily there are a bunch of USB hubs that expand the number of ports you can have. This one allows you to hide a USB storage device inside and provides 3 USB A and 2 USB C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/32L9KWZ&quot;&gt;All Weather Tesla Model 3 Floor Mats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07KYXCD23/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=8e83832c0dd3f03a1440c64497cc39ad&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B07KYXCD23&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; alt=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLink&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B07KYXCD23&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLink&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was originally planning on ordering &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.tesla.com/product/model-3-all-weather-floor-liners&quot;&gt;floor mats from Tesla&lt;/a&gt;, but I changed my mind once I saw the price. While the Tesla ones look a lot cooler, I couldn&apos;t justify spending an extra $150 on floor mats. These get the job done and keep my car nice and clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3eXhk32&quot;&gt;Tesla Model 3 Tempered Glass Screen Protector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07GKGDC5M/ref=as_li_ss_il?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=42017d3dc3f1164040f4192645d73851&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B07GKGDC5M&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; alt=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLink&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B07GKGDC5M&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLink&quot;  style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes a scratched phone screen so why risk that happening to your car display too? It was easy to install, but it took a week for the air bubbles to go away. No complaints here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3fWlN7D&quot;&gt;Tesla Model 3 Wireless Charger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/TapTes-Wireless-Smartphone-Accessories-Compatible/dp/B07Q9L6DJN/ref=as_li_ss_il?crid=1LFSWCXG67W87&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=model+3+wireless+charging+pad&amp;qid=1595551587&amp;s=automotive&amp;sprefix=model+3+wire,automotive,215&amp;sr=1-2-spons&amp;psc=1&amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzM0JaWDdPRjVBV1MwJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwNDIzNzA5MzhCS05RRThGS0tLUCZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwOTE2NDE2OExQUFhVSTBIRlZPJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ==&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=aefd49a03b1a1a268d6727c9286643a8&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B07Q9L6DJN&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; alt=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLink&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B07Q9L6DJN&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLink&quot;  style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s so convenient being able drop your phone in the charging pad without having to deal with plugging your phone in. It&apos;s so convenient if your friends don&apos;t use the same phone as you and you don&apos;t have the USB cable for their phones. While wireless charging isn&apos;t as fast as wired charging, I still think the convenience factor outweighs the charging speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Benefits from Buying from Referral Link&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you purchase a Tesla using someone&apos;s referral link, both parties earn 1,000 miles of free Supercharging. Since new Model 3s don&apos;t come with free Supercharging anymore, having some free credits is a nice to have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s my &lt;a href=&quot;https://ts.la/anthony85679&quot;&gt;Referral Link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Overall Build Quality is Meager&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, in order to mass produce the car, Tesla had to compensate on quality. One of my seat belts doesn&apos;t work and I&apos;m afraid to take my car into repairs since I heard rumors that repair time could take a long time. Another nit I have is the car doesn&apos;t feel like a luxury car. Since the car is so barebones, it doesn&apos;t have the same cabin luxury as other cars in the same price point. Also, I take pretty good care of my car, but I still have random scratches on my car. I ended up buying &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.tesla.com/product/paint-repair-kit&quot;&gt;extra paint&lt;/a&gt; to cover some of these scratches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also purchased a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tesla.com/support/model-3-key-fob&quot;&gt;Model 3 Key Fob&lt;/a&gt;, but it didn&apos;t work. The key was able start my car by putting it where the key card should go, but the buttons on the fob didn&apos;t work. I assume I got a faulty key so I ended up sending it back and it took almost 3 months to get my money back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Lack of Blind Spot Detection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/uFfr9xE&quot; alt=&quot;Blind Spot&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish there was some sort of blind spot detection feature. The car doesn&apos;t beep if you&apos;re merging into a lane and a car is in your blind spot. The car doesn&apos;t have any notifications or displays when a car is in your blind spot. Even my previous car, a Volkswagen Jetta, had this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. The 0-60 on the SR+ isn’t as Fast as the Dual Motor Models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tesla Model 3 Performance model can hit 0-60 in 3.2 seconds. However, don&apos;t expect the base model to have these kinds of speeds. My Standard Range Plus hits 0-60 in about 5.3 seconds which isn&apos;t slow, but I wish it was a bit faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s a breakdown of the 0-60 for all the Model 3s. I got this info from &lt;a href=&quot;https://insideevs.com/reviews/343552/tesla-model-3-0-to-60-mph-how-quick-is-it-compared-to-other-teslas/&quot;&gt;Inside Evs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;0-60&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Standard Range (2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.6 seconds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Standard Range Plus (2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.3 seconds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Long Range RWD (2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0 seconds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Long Range AWD (2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.5 seconds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Performance LR AWD (2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.2 seconds&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. People Love Breaking into Model 3s&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in late 2019 and early 2020, there was a surge of car break-ins in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercurynews.com/2020/01/09/multi-city-rash-of-car-break-ins-hits-the-bay-area/&quot;&gt;Bay Area&lt;/a&gt;. This was extremely common with &lt;a href=&quot;https://electrek.co/2019/01/16/tesla-vehicles-target-break-ins-solutions/&quot;&gt;Model 3s&lt;/a&gt; due to the lack of actual sensors that detect broken car windows. Even my friend in the Bay Area got his Model 3 broken into. To fix curb this issue, Tesla introduced Sentry Mode. Sentry Mode uses the car&apos;s cameras to watch for any offending activity and uses some sensors to detect if the car is being broken into. While better than nothing, Sentry Mode isn&apos;t perfect. It sometimes doesn&apos;t trigger and video can get corrupt. Also, battery drain is pretty bad. 1 hour of use drains about 1 mile of drive time.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How I Landed Offers from Facebook, Google, Uber, & Microsoft as a Software Engineer]]></title><description><![CDATA[I still remember applying to Facebook every year and getting rejected and how bad I flunked my interview with Google during my senior year…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/how-i-got-multiple-fang-offers-e0a87898</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/how-i-got-multiple-fang-offers-e0a87898</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I still remember applying to Facebook every year and getting rejected and how bad I flunked my interview with Google during my senior year of college. Well good news is that studying actually paid off because in I had the opportunity to interview with some of my dream companies back in 2017. I interviewed with Microsoft, Uber, Facebook, and Google and I received offers from all of them. I had actually so many interviews lined up that I ended up not proceeding with most of the companies like Apple and Amazon. I wanted to share my experiences, my study routine, and my thoughts on each company in order to help you guys join your dream company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preparing for Your Next Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One big was surprised transitioning from intern life to full time was the difficulty in the interview questions. I honestly was not prepared for that when I interviewed for companies my Senior year of college. From my epic failures, I learned that I needed to prepare weeks in advance instead of days. As a Software Engineer with a full time job, I found it really difficult to find time to prepare. Back when I was working at Intuit, I typically worked from 9am - 7pm. That only gave me around 3 hours to prepare during the weekday. To compensate for this, I spend my entire weekend just studying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Updating your Resume&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s start with the first step which is to update your resume. Here are some tips to update your resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save your current job description. These job descriptions have a pretty good rundown of your responsibilities and skills. They also have a lot of keywords that recruiters look for. You will want to have these keywords on your resume since resumes get filtered through a system that looks for those keywords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show off business outcomes when possible. Metrics like &quot;I created feature x which increased engagement by y%&quot; are nice to haves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&apos;re a front end/full stack developer, having a portfolio is a nice way to show case your skills. Here&apos;s a link to my old &lt;a href=&quot;http://ajw029.github.io/#/&quot;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt;. You don&apos;t need to spend a single dollar on it if you use Github Pages. Here&apos;s a guide on &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/how-to-host-a-website-for-free-5165ea28&quot;&gt;setting up your website on Github Pages for free&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only put down achievements you accomplished. If an interviewer asks about an item your teammates did and you cannot answer, it&apos;s usually a red flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, only list projects you&apos;re comfortable explaining to a nonprogrammer. If you can&apos;t explain the project in simple terms, then it might come off as if you don&apos;t understand what you created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Study for Technical Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s a lot to study for the technical interviews. You gotta brush up on algorithms, system design, and whiteboarding skills. I started my adventures on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codewars.com/&quot;&gt;Codewars&lt;/a&gt; which similar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://leetcode.com/&quot;&gt;LeetCode&lt;/a&gt;, but has a lot easier problems to start with. This helped refresh my memory on basic algorithms and solving basic interview questions. I also shared a &lt;a href=&quot;https://leetcode.com/subscribe/&quot;&gt;LeetCode Premium&lt;/a&gt; account with my friend. My favorite part about LeetCode Premium was it shows topics and types of questions some companies like to ask. This can help you target your studies towards your dream company better. Honestly, $35 a month isn&apos;t that much in comparison to how much you&apos;ll make once you work for a FANG company. I only studied for 3 months so that only came out to be $105.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to LeetCoding, I read a couple of books to refresh on basic algorithms. I noticed I got really distracted whenever I read books or pdfs on my computer, so I found myself checking Reddit or Facebook every couple of minutes. Since you&apos;ll only have 3 hours to study I suggest getting a physical copy or buy a dedicated e-reader. This really helped me focus since I wasn&apos;t tinkering on my computer with multiple windows open. Here&apos;s the list of devices and books I used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;amazon-affiliate&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=0984782850&amp;asins=0984782850&amp;linkId=ee3d25386cf6d455575d79f48c2d9a27&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=1783554878&amp;asins=1783554878&amp;linkId=fabb7959ed3a1e07ee902ba839454e51&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B07978J597&amp;asins=B07978J597&amp;linkId=2930671de01fa789a03db810a30a0365&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/amazon-affiliate&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s some of my tips and tricks that I learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purchase a whiteboard to practice on. Coding on a whiteboard is a different experience compared to coding on your computer. You can&apos;t easily copy paste code nor can you run your code. Practicing on the whiteboard has helped me practice jotting down all my ideas before starting the implementation. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat problems that you couldn&apos;t figure out the first time. In fact, I would recommend redoing problems you couldn&apos;t figure out two weeks later. This helped me solidify that I understood the concepts rather than memorizing the problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check other people&apos;s solutions. I picked up a lot of elegant coding practices just by looking at other people&apos;s code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a &quot;short&quot; language. What I mean by short is something that isn&apos;t verbose. I used ES6 for all of my interviews this time. I really liked how I didn&apos;t have to define my types and write unnecessary code like &quot;public void doSomething()&quot; just to define a function. Plus you have limited space on a whiteboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start studying with the fundamentals. Avoid the tough stuff until you&apos;re comfortable with the bread and butter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course theres a billion things you need to study, but here&apos;s a list of the main topics I focused on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linked Lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;String Problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stacks/Queues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph Theory (DFS, BFS, Dijkstra)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trees&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sorting Algorithm (Good to know one O(n^2) algorithm and one O(nlogn))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greedy Algorithm (Most of them follow the same pattern, so just understand one really well.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic Programming (I didn&apos;t spend much time on this area since I found this topic hit or miss.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;System Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These problems tend to be open ended. The interviewer gives you some sort of scenario or a real world problem and will ask you to &quot;design&quot; it. I usually start by listing out use cases. Let&apos;s say the interviewer asks you to create Youtube. There&apos;s a lot of parts of Youtube so just list all of them that come to your mind. Once you have all those features, I would start eliminating features that are not part of &quot;core&quot; features. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually learned how to answer System Design questions by watching Youtubers walkthrough some problems. Here&apos;s a video that I found pretty helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;youtube id=&quot;fMZMm_0ZhK4&quot;&gt;&lt;youtube&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Phone Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Recruiter&apos;s Phone Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After applying to a company, a recruiter will email you to chat. Usually your first phone calls is a non-technical interview with a recruiter. This call is mainly to find out your availability for interviews. Depending on your situation, you can tell the recruiter one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&apos;re currently not looking for a new opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&apos;re interested, but you&apos;ll need some time to prepare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&apos;re interested and you&apos;re currently interviewing with other companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last option tells the recruiters that you need to interview with their company as soon as possible and potentially skip the phone interview. I actually skipped the phone interview with Google because I told my recruiter I already had onsites scheduled with Facebook, Uber, and Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Technical Phone Interviews&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of technical phone interviews were more or less the same. You spend 45 minutes to 1 hour with an engineer to code up some problems on a Coderpad or a Google Doc. If you do well then you&apos;ll move onto the onsite. I would recommend starting phone interviews with companies you are least interested in first. That way you can practice and gauge how well you&apos;re doing. Also, since the interviewer can’t see you, it’s important to explain your thought process and how you plan to tackle the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some takeaways&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The recruiters want you to do well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask for as much time as you need. I asked Google, Facebook, and Uber for 3 months to prepare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start interviewing with your least favorite companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The On-site Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On-site interviews vary company to company, but for the most part, you and an interviewer interact in solving a problem on a whiteboard. Most companies have about 4-5 technical interviews and sometimes a System Design question depending on your level. These interviews are back to back with a lunch break in-between. While you don&apos;t want to eat too much, actually try out some of the food because if you join that company you&apos;re going to be eating their food for many years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t start these problems by busting out code. Start by writing down all the ideas that come to my head. For example, if they ask you to get the top K elements of an array, just write down all the ideas that come to your head even if they sound crazy. This will also allow you and your interviewer to bounce ideas off each other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another trick I learned along the way is if you&apos;re unsure of the most optimized answer or an answer in general, start with the brute force solution. Once you figure that out, try to bounce ideas off with your interviewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Microsoft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/ZdLnIls&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft logo&quot; title=&quot;Microsoft&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually didn&apos;t apply to Microsoft. Rather Microsoft reached out to me for a hiring event. Instead of doing a phone interview, I had to complete an online coding assignment in an hour. After I finished the assignment, the recruiter reached out to chat and scheduled a date for an onsite interview. Microsoft flew me to Redmond and paid for the flight, food, and the hotel. I came in a day earlier to check out the city, visited common tourist areas, and I even stopped by the original Starbucks shop. ‪The next day, I came for the on-site, which had 4 rounds with each being 45 minutes long. I also had a System Design round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/YCkiMws&quot; alt=&quot;Google logo&quot; title=&quot;Google&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was actually the 2nd time I interviewed with Google. The first time did not go so well, so I really wanted to redeem myself this time. Also, since I had other on-sites coming up and an offer from Microsoft, Google let me skip the phone interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I interviewed at the Sunnyvale site which is where their Google Cloud team is located. The on-site had 4 rounds with each round being 45 minutes long. They also have a Googler take you out to lunch at the Google cafeteria after the 2nd interview. I would say this was the hardest of all my interviews. I heard Google has a behavioral round to gauge your Googleyness now, but I didn&apos;t have one of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you finish your interviews, the interviewers submit their feedback and it goes into a packet for a hiring committee to review. If they give the thumbs up, then you start the project fit calls. These calls are pretty informal where you and a potential manager chat about the team and what you want to do. After these calls, you select one of them that you&apos;re most interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Uber&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/nVaWq1q&quot; alt=&quot;Uber logo&quot; title=&quot;Uber&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber has a couple of offices with some in Palo Alto, but their main HQ is in SF which is where they conducted the interviews. But thankfully, Uber was considerate enough to provide me with $200 of Uber credits so I didn&apos;t have to worry about driving to SF and back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber&apos;s on-site consists of 3 technical rounds and 2 behavioral rounds. They allowed me to bring my laptop and code out their coding questions on my device. I really enjoyed this since it felt more practical. I also liked having 45 minutes to just talk with the manager and a cultural bar raiser. The cultural bar raiser is someone at Uber who isn&apos;t on the team I&apos;m interviewing for. Talking to him gave me an opportunity to learn about what others thought about the company. It felt like they really value culture fit as much as technical prowess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Facebook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/4zmTidc.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Facebook logo&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interview took place at Building 10 inside of the Classic campus. Facebook&apos;s campus has the biggest wow factor. Seriously, Facebook Classic is amazing. I seriously felt like I just walked into Disneyland. They literally have everything on campus including a sweet shop, a health center, a Phillz, a barber shop, an arcade, pop up shops, and way more that I have not covered. Check out some pictures &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/facebooks-disneyland-inspired-campus-2013-10#the-bike-shops-vending-machine-has-bike-parts-like-tire-tubes-brake-pads-chain-links-48&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the interview was pretty long consisting of 5 rounds. I had 1 system design question and the rest were all coding questions. Each interviewer asked about two coding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Negotiating the Offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would recommend scheduling all your interviews as closely as possible. It will make negotiating a lot easier since you&apos;ll have most of your offers at the same time. The key to negotiating is having more than one offer. Having patience is also important. Recruiters will try to pressure you to accept an offer as soon as possible, but you can tell them you&apos;re still waiting to hear back from all the other companies to buy some time. Once you have all your offers, you can use your offers to increase each other. For example, if company A offers you $100k and company B offers you $120k, you can use the offer from company B to increase the offer from company A. Generally big companies don&apos;t match offers from startups since their stocks are not liquid yet, but this strategy worked well for me regardless. One big mistake I made was giving out my expectations; if a recruiter pushes for a number, try to push it off. Offers usually consists of base salary, a targeted bonus, a sign on bonus, and equity. Targeted bonus is paid out annually based on your performance. If the target is at 15% and your base salary is 100k, then your bonus is 15000. Equity usually vests over a certain time period. So, the company may offer $10000 worth of stocks over 4 years and lets assume the stock price is $1 when you started. This means you have 10000 shares. However, you will only earn 2500 shares every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links in Article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ZPWq1O&quot;&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2CZ75yc&quot;&gt;Learning JavaScript Data Structures and Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2WM5KBP&quot;&gt;Kindle Paperwhite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Four Year Plan at UCSD as a Computer Science Major]]></title><description><![CDATA[Back as a freshman I wasn't sure what courses I should take. There's a bunch of required major courses and college requirements to graduate…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/four-year-plan-ucsd-computer-science-major-45a6bc11</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/four-year-plan-ucsd-computer-science-major-45a6bc11</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Back as a freshman I wasn&apos;t sure what courses I should take. There&apos;s a bunch of required major courses and college requirements to graduate, but which ones should I take? You can work with your guidance counselor on drafting a 4 year plan, but I think it&apos;s more useful to see a 4 year plan from an actual alumni.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was admitted to Revelle College in UCSD in Fall quarter of 2012 as a Computer Engineering major. I actually started out as a Computer Engineering major and switched to a Computer Science major. You can learn more about the difference in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&apos;t have that many AP credits so I couldn&apos;t skip a lot of college requirements. To give you guys an insight on the courses I took during High School, I&apos;ll list out some of the AP courses &amp;#x26; Summer courses I took and their UCSD equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;UCSD equivalent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AP Chemistry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CHEM 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AP Calc AB&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MATH 20A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AP Physics B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PHYS 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Computer Programming (Community College)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 8A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&apos;t a comprehensive list of all the courses that can be transferred. If you&apos;re curious on which credits you can transfer over check out these links: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucsd.edu/catalog/pdf/APC-chart.pdf&quot;&gt;Transferable AP Credit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://assist.org&quot;&gt;Transferable Credits from Other Universities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not going to list the Professor since a lot has change since 2012, but I&apos;ll mention some noteworthy professors to avoid or recommend. I would use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/&quot;&gt;RateMyProfessors&lt;/a&gt; to check for any red flags when figuring out which courses to take and with who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fall Quarter 2012&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/E5qKOav&quot; alt=&quot;UCSD Bear&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SDCC 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P/NP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MATH 20B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ANTH 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You guys are probably wondering what is that SDCC course. Well UCSD has this &quot;UC Entry Level writing requirement&quot; and I didn&apos;t satisfy that requirement coming in so I had to take a make up course. At the end of the quarter, you&apos;ll need to take an exam and if you pass that exam you&apos;ll fulfill that requirement. Unfortunately, I didn&apos;t pass that exam so I had to take it again in the Winter Quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I took CSE 11, we had weekly coding projects and quizzes. I didn&apos;t find it too difficult since the assignments were coded in Java and I was already familiar with Java. This class is meant for students who passed their AP Computer Science course. I would suggest taking CSE 11 if possible since you&apos;ll be able to skip both CSE 8A and 8B saving you an extra quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took ANTH 1 to fulfill some of Revelle College&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://revelle.ucsd.edu/academics/general-education/soc-science.html&quot;&gt;Social Science Requirements&lt;/a&gt;. I honestly don&apos;t remember too much about this course, but majority of the content came from lecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Winter Quarter 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SDCC 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P/NP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MATH 20C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 15L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 91&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P/NP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this looks like a lot of courses, I honestly think this wasn&apos;t that much workload. I honestly don&apos;t remember too much about CSE 91, but every week a guest author would come and talk about their experiences in the Computer Science industry. CSE 91 has no coding assignments so the bulk of my work came from CSE 12. I probably could&apos;ve taken another course and made it out alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I passed SDCC this quarter. I still struggled with it my second time, but I&apos;m glad I passed the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 12 and 15L were pretty difficult at the time. These courses go over the basics of Object Oriented Design and Data Structures. Be sure to learn these concepts since you&apos;ll use Arrays, Linked Lists, and Graphs the rest of your career. Interviewers love to ask questions surrounding these concepts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spring Quarter 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MATH 20D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PHYS 2A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took MATH 20D since it was required for ECE 35 and it&apos;s not a requirement for Computer Science majors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had to take PHYS 2A so I could take PHYS 4B which was a prerequisite for ECE 35 as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really disliked CSE 20 since it was theory based. I wrote a bunch proofs and learned about number systems and induction. Even though I got an A- in this course, I honestly don&apos;t remember a thing from this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 30 is no joke. Having to learn assembly has a big learning curve and many consider CSE 30 and CSE 20 to be a weeder course. I&apos;ll agree with those statements. To be honest, at the time I thought this was the hardest course I took yet, but things got much more difficult from this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summer 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;UCSD Equivalent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HIST 4B (Foothill)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HUM 4 or 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PHYS 4B (West Valley)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PHYS 2B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the summer, I took the equivalent to PHYS 2B at a community college so I take ECE 35. I also took a course on Western Civ (4B from Foothill College) which could be used for one of my HUM courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fall Quarter 2013&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ECE 35&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P/NP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LTKO 1A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VIS 60&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 21 was also very theoretical. It also felt like a precursor to CSE 101. I learned some basics for writing proofs for runtime analysis and probability in this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ECE 35 was definitely the hardest course I took at UCSD. The course started with like 200 students and over 50% dropped the course. I changed my major from Computer Engineering to Computer Science and switched it to Pass/No Pass since I wasn&apos;t sure if I was going to pass the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took Korean and Photography to start fulfilling some of Revelle&apos;s College requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Winter Quarter 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 110&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LTKO 1B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HUM 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Humanity courses are no joke. I had to read the entire Old Testament in one quarter and the course is worth 6 units! I got a B+ that quarter and it dropped my GPA a bit. HUM 1 was seriously a lot of work and I hated that course with a passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re a CS major, I recommend paying attention in CSE 100. You&apos;ll start to understand Leetcode Medium questions by taking this course. You&apos;ll learn the basics of Heaps, Graph Theory, and Graph Search algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 110 was one of my favorite courses at UCSD. The professor gives you guys a theme and you form a group with other students to build an app on that theme. My team built an Android App that sent you reminders when you reached certain destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spring Quarter 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/5EhsihX&quot; alt=&quot;CSE 101&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 101&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MATH 20F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LTKO 1C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HUM 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HUM 2 isn&apos;t any easier than HUM 1. You&apos;ll have to read a bunch of novels and epics and write a ton of essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 101 (Design and Analysis of Algorithms) was pretty difficult to understand. You&apos;ll learn the basics of Graph theory like DFS, BFS, and other graph algorithms. I took the course with Professor Dasgupta and I wish the course spent more time on coding the algorithms rather than writing proofs. To be completely honest, most people who take this course relearn this material on their own. I used the following resources to learn advance Algorithms and Data Structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLinksContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=0984782850&amp;asins=0984782850&amp;linkId=ee3d25386cf6d455575d79f48c2d9a27&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=1783554878&amp;asins=1783554878&amp;linkId=fabb7959ed3a1e07ee902ba839454e51&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summer 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/mPdbsGA&quot; alt=&quot;Coupons Internship&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;UCSD Equivalent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HIST 4A (Foothill)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HUM 3, 4, or 5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MUSI 1 (Foothill)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MUS 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MUSI 3A (Foothill)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MUS 1A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually started my first Computer Science Internship during the summer of 2014. I would recommend reading this article to learn more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/things-wish-knew-before-going-ucsd-computer-science-major-5ee2265f&quot;&gt;Computer Science Internships&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took courses over the summer to make sure I was on track to graduate in 2016. I mainly took those Music courses to satisfy the &lt;a href=&quot;https://revelle.ucsd.edu/academics/general-education/fine-arts.html&quot;&gt;Fine Arts Requirements&lt;/a&gt; and so I could take MUS 173.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fall Quarter 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 90&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P/NP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 103&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;LTKO 2A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HUM 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&apos;re probably wondering why I took so many Korean courses. Well Revelle has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://revelle.ucsd.edu/academics/general-education/language.html&quot;&gt;Language Requirement&lt;/a&gt; and I needed to complete 4 quarters worth of Language courses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly don&apos;t remember why I took CSE 90. I think it might have been required if you wanted to tutor for CSE courses. I don&apos;t think I even had a final or actual assignments for this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 103 was the Upper Div course for Probability and Statistics. You&apos;ll learn about counting and basic fundamentals of statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 120 was a pretty difficult course since you&apos;ll need to learn a lot of low level concepts. There were a bunch of Masters students taking this course along with us too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can only take 2 HUM equivalent courses outside of UCSD (excluding HUM 1 and HUM 2). Thankfully, HUM 3 isn&apos;t as difficult or time intensive as HUM 1 or HUM 2. It&apos;s still a lot of work since you need to read a lot, but don&apos;t expect it to be as extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Winter Quarter 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 124&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 132A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 140&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 140L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to wrap up most of my General Electives by this quarter so I started taking a lot more CSE courses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer Science majors are required to take 7 electives. Read more about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucsd.edu/catalog/curric/CSE-ug.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Up until this point, I was taking my required Core Courses. I took CSE 132A to fulfill some of those elective requirements. I recommend taking at least one Database courses like CSE 132A to get familiar with SQL and good DB practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 140 was one of those courses I wondered why Computer Science students were required to take. After working in the industry for a couple of years, I can better appreciate this course. I advise you to avoid taking this course with Professor Orailoglu if possible. We used Verilog to understand basic digital hardware abstraction and logic gates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spring Quarter 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ANTH 23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;BILD 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 123&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 105 was one of those courses where you had to write a bunch of proofs. Since I was really bad at that, I decided to slim down on the number of CSE courses this quarter. This course contains material regarding deterministic algorithms, turing machines, and finite state machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 123 one of those courses I took to fulfill the Upper Div Electives requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took BILD 3 to fulfill some of Revelle College&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://revelle.ucsd.edu/academics/general-education/nat-science.html&quot;&gt;Natural Science Requirements&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summer 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/ZtAvuCu&quot; alt=&quot;Intuit&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 197&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;P/NP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a summer internship during 2015 while taking CSE 197. CSE is an easy 4 unit Pass/No Pass course that counts towards your Upper Div Electives. You&apos;re eligible if you&apos;re doing a Computer Science internship and all you need to do is blog about your internship experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fall Quarter 2015&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 134B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 141&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 141L&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took CSE 134B to fulfill my Upper Div Electives. Honestly, this was one of the BEST courses offered at UCSD. If Professor Powell is teaching this course, I highly recommend taking this course with him. This was my introduction to Web Development and honestly one of my favorite courses at UCSD. I learned a lot about Fullstack Development and good JavaScript practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, CSE 141 is another one of those hardware related courses. CSE 141 delves mainly into the theory, but CSE 141L is more hands on with coding. You&apos;ll learn a lot about CPU design from logic gates. CSE 141L is definitely the more difficult of the two since you need to code using Verilog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Winter Quarter 2016&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COGS 187A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MUS 173&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 130&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took COGS 187A and MUS 173 to fulfill my Upper Div Electives. I couldn&apos;t find MUS 173 as an acceptable elective on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucsd.edu/catalog/curric/CSE-ug.html&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; anymore, but I would check with your guidance counselor to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MUS 173 was mainly about electronic music production. You&apos;ll learn how to create music using Ableton Live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend taking COGS 187A if you&apos;re into Front End Development. You&apos;ll learn about core principals regarding information architecture, navigation, and interaction. I believe this is really important to learn so you can develop good products for real users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 130 was a fun course. You&apos;ll learn about functional programming and play around with different programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spring Quarter 2016&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Units&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 136&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 135&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 131&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took both CSE 136 and CSE 135 for finish my Upper Div Electives. CSE 136 was pretty similar to CSE 134B and CSE 135 was pretty similar to CSE 132A. I mainly took those courses because I was already comfortable with those concepts and I knew I would spend my entire quarter focusing on CSE 131. One diff between CSE 135 and 132A is that you&apos;ll actually make a Web App and Server that uses a SQL database. I honestly preferred this course over 132A.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/aQcGMpV&quot; alt=&quot;CSE 131&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSE 131 was the hardest course I took at UCSD. It uses everything you learned in CSE 105, CSE 141, and CSE 120 to build a compiler from scratch. Each project builds on top of each other as well. Usually, when you finish a project you start a new one from scratch, but in CSE 131, you&apos;ll need to make sure your previous assignments are functional to continue your current assignment. I&apos;m pretty sure I spent over 40 hours a week on the assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that requirements change year over year. Back in the day, we had more requirements which is why I have a lot more courses counting towards Upper Div Electives. I think we also needed to take CSE 120 and (CSE 123 or CSE 124) and those didn&apos;t count towards the Upper Div Electives. Here&apos;s a list of all the courses I took that count towards the Upper Div Electives requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Upper Div Electives&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 123&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 124&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 132A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 134B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 135&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 136&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 197&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COGS 187A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MUS 173&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduating isn&apos;t an easy task and having a plan will definitely help you stay on track. I hope my 4 year plan has given some insight on how to structure your own plan. Did you graduate from UCSD as well? What did you do to graduate on time? Let me know in the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Guide to Landing Your Computer Science Internship and What to Expect]]></title><description><![CDATA[Why should I work for a company when I can enjoy my summer break? Well internships provide first hand exposure to working in the real world…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/guide-computer-science-internship-and-expectations-2e2358ef</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/guide-computer-science-internship-and-expectations-2e2358ef</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Why should I work for a company when I can enjoy my summer break? Well internships provide first hand exposure to working in the real world. You&apos;ll learn to actually use the concepts taught in your university. Most importantly, you&apos;ll acquire new skills and knowledge that will be used to advance your career even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about how I got my internships, let&apos;s look into why companies hire interns in the first place. There&apos;s a common misconception that interns are hired because they&apos;re cheap labor. While this may be true with a startup with 3 people and no funding, this is definitely not the case for most companies. Hiring interns is a great opportunity for companies to scout for potential talent and groom them. It&apos;s much cheaper for a company to find potential hires and train an intern for 3 months than hiring an industry hire and having to fire them if they don&apos;t work out. Now that we know why companies look for interns, let&apos;s see what I did to land my internships. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Getting Noticed by Companies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to get onto the company&apos;s radar you&apos;ll need to actually apply to the companies. Most people are afraid that they&apos;re not good enough, but it&apos;s better to get a rejection than never knowing the outcome. I highly recommend networking and attending Job Fairs since you&apos;ll be able to meet actual people and interact with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my first internship by networking and reaching out to people who were already working in the industry. I went to all the job fairs at my university and interviewed with a couple of companies like Yahoo and Microsoft, but didn&apos;t have any luck since most companies were looking for juniors or found stronger candidates. I believe networking is extremely important when you&apos;re starting out because there are a ton of students all trying to get an internship and having a person vouch for you is important. This is not to say knowing people will land you an internship since you&apos;ll still need a solid resume and background. During my junior year, I got my internship at Intuit by attending a job fair. I talked to at least 10 companies at the job fair, but Microsoft, Yahoo, and Intuit were the only companies that reached out. To be completely honest, I completely flunked my Yahoo and Microsoft interviews and I wasn&apos;t expecting Intuit&apos;s recruiter to reach out to me. Having going to many of these job fairs and actually participating in hiring myself, I think I have a list of common signals used for hiring. Let&apos;s look at a couple of signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Having a Stellar Resume&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One big mistake I used to make was putting all the projects I worked on. Instead you should pick and choose projects that you&apos;re comfortable explaining and showcases your highlights. If a recruiter or interviewer asks about a project, you should be comfortable with explaining the ins and outs as well as your role in the project. Most universities have a general GPA and a major GPA. I generally suggest using the higher GPA. If both are good then put both of them on your resume. If you&apos;re not talking to a recruiter in person, your resume will be filtered through a system. This system scans for keywords to see how compatible the person is for the position. You can run your resume against an ATS to evaluate how well your resume fair. I recommend using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jobscan.co/&quot;&gt;jobscan.co&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Having Personal Projects To Make You Stand Out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This signals ties into the projects section of your resume. All the Computer Science majors in your university are required to take the same courses as you. Imagine what a recruiter thinks when they sift through thousands of resumes and everyone lists the same project from that CSE 30 course. How can a recruiter determine which candidate is better if they all have the same exact projects? As a result, you&apos;ll need to have personal projects or other internships to differentiate yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communication Skills&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can be the most amazing coder in the world, but if you&apos;re not able to describe your work and your skills properly, no one will take you seriously. Being able to relay your skills and projects to a non Computer Science major will help recruiters understand your level of expertise and knowledge. It also can show how well you understand the project and technologies as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to Expect From a Computer Science Interview for Interns&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you impress a recruiter, you&apos;ll move onto the next phase: the interview. Some companies have interviewers do a first round of interviews on campus and then fly you out to their headquarters for an onsite interview. Some companies just do one round of interviews. This is really dependent on the company so do your research. I would suggest you practice doing some &lt;a href=&quot;https://leetcode.com/&quot;&gt;LeetCode&lt;/a&gt; problems months in advance. I used to cram and practice a bunch of LeetCode problems the day before the interview and that never worked out for me. From my experience, interviewers generally ask LeetCode Easy problems for Sophomores and a combination of LeetCode Easy and Medium for Juniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Sophomore I would recommend being comfortable with using Arrays, LinkedLists, and Recursion. The most common question I got as a Sophomore was to reverse a LinkedList or to reverse a string or list. As a Junior I would recommend taking an Advanced Data Structures and Algorithms course as early as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got a lot of behavioral questions like &quot;tell me about a time you had a conflict and how you resolved it&quot; or &quot;tell me about a big accomplishment and why that one.&quot; I honestly have no idea how much weight these questions have, but I guess they&apos;re used to see if the candidate would be a good culture fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I&apos;m glad I failed a lot of interviews my Sophomore and Junior year because it helped me realize the algorithms and data structures I really struggled with. I also learned that I needed to study months in advance before conducting the interview. I used the resources below to pass my full time interviews with Facebook, Google, and Microsoft. You might not have learned a lot of the concepts in these books, but I still recommend reading the early chapters for basic algorithms and data structure.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLinksContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=0984782850&amp;asins=0984782850&amp;linkId=ee3d25386cf6d455575d79f48c2d9a27&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=1783554878&amp;asins=1783554878&amp;linkId=fabb7959ed3a1e07ee902ba839454e51&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Accepting the Offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you pass your interviews and the company has headcount, the recruiter will follow up with an offer. When I interned at Coupons.com, I was offered $28 an hour. When I interned at Intuit, I was offered $35 an hour. Intuit even offered housing, a rental car, and free gas for all the interns for 3 months. Even full time employees don&apos;t get these kinds of benefits! Generally it&apos;s hard to negotiate for a higher pay unless you have multiple offers on hand. If you&apos;re going to relocate to a different state for the internship, you&apos;re generally eligible for a relocation fee. I wouldn&apos;t worry about the compensation too much because the experience will be more beneficial in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to Expect from the Internship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/mPdbsGA&quot; alt=&quot;Coupons&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you&apos;ve accepted your offer you&apos;re probably wondering what comes next. Most internships will require you to be with the team and last for 3 months. Your experience will vary between companies and teams, but I&apos;ll share my experiences as an intern. At Coupons, I worked on building a reconciliation tool. It was built with Java and I had to learn about Cassandra, REST, and XML. This tool was it&apos;s own separate repo and didn&apos;t touch the production code (although I did touch production servers). At Intuit, I also worked on building a health monitoring tool which monitors production systems for abnormal behavior. This was built using Java, MongoDB, and Spring Boot. In both of my internships, neither of my mentors reviewed my pull requests which was disappointing since I was hoping to learn good programming practices. Looking back, I should&apos;ve had 1 on 1s with my mentors and let them know of some of my expectations from the internship. Don&apos;t be afraid to ask your mentors for these things! Let your mentors know what you want to get out of the internship and what you want to learn. The internship should be beneficial to both parties. I also noticed that a lot of interns start out writing tests as their starter project in order to learn more about the system and the infrastructure. I personally think this is a great way to introduce engineers to writing tests because most universities don&apos;t teach good practices on testing in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/3Dg1X6X&quot; alt=&quot;Free Food&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some fun perks that you&apos;ll probably get include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bunch of swag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Events for just the interns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coffee and Snacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve compiled a list of other things you&apos;ll most likely run into during your internship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You&apos;ll Be Solving a Well Defined Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your hosts won&apos;t be giving you a project that they can&apos;t solve themselves. Intern project are scoped to be finished within 3 months and take into consideration the intern&apos;s skill level. If your hosts are giving you project that cannot be completed within the 3 months, work with your hosts to reduce the scope. Usually, the hosts will need to submit a review of their intern to the recruiters. Having a project that can be completed will work towards your benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Using Version Control System&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us don&apos;t really learn how to use version control like Git or Mercurial until we&apos;re thrown into the workforce. Even when I was attending my university, I just force pushed into the master branch without proper Git commit messages. This won&apos;t fly in a company&apos;s codebase. You&apos;ll need to have proper commit messages and learn how to manage your branches the right way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Learning How to Test Your Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like version control, most of us don&apos;t write proper unit tests or integration tests for our school projects. The majority of my assignments already had tests written and we were expected to implement the skeleton code to make the tests pass. In fact, a lot of production codebases have checks to make sure you have enough code coverage or else you won&apos;t be able to check in your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Expect to Learn New Tools and Concepts.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every project and team has different requirements. As a result, the team might already be on a specific tech stack that you&apos;ll have to learn. Sometimes you get lucky and you can start a repo from scratch, but regardless you&apos;ll most likely be learning new libraries and frameworks to implement your solution. Be open to learning these new concepts since these are things your university probably won&apos;t teach you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Return Offer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re a junior or sometimes a senior who&apos;s graduating late, you might be given an offer for a full time position. How does one get a return offer? Well I was lucky enough to get a return offer when I interned at Intuit. Your host and manager will be making the final decision. Make sure you have weekly syncs to make sure both you and your manager are aligned. You can also ask about the steps you&apos;ll need to take to get a return offer and hopefully your manager will work with you on establishing those expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you have a better idea what your internship may look like. The road will be long and hard, but it&apos;ll be worth it in the end. Remember to have fun learning new things during your internship. How was your internships like? What were some difficulties you encountered in landing your internship? What other questions do you guys have? Let me know in the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Interesting Things I Wish I Knew Before Going to UCSD]]></title><description><![CDATA[1. Parking is a Competitive Sport Gilman There are a couple of parking lots at UCSD. You'll also need to pay for a permit every quarter to…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/interesting-things-wish-knew-before-going-ucsd-5ee2265f</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/interesting-things-wish-knew-before-going-ucsd-5ee2265f</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;1. Parking is a Competitive Sport&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/trips_photos/blog_images/75578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gilman&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of parking lots at UCSD. You&apos;ll also need to pay for a permit every quarter to be able to park. Not all parking spaces are equal either. There are spots for Student, Staff, Visitor, etc.  Gilman Parking Structure is the main parking lot for commuters, but don&apos;t expect to find parking without struggling. The S spots lot generally fill up in the morning. People even joke around that parking is a competitive sport at UCSD! I know some commuters didn&apos;t want to bother with this so they parked off campus and took the shuttle to campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. There Isn&apos;t Much to Do Around Campus Without a Car&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/trips_photos/blog_images/sungod_birb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sungod Bird&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s a bunch to do in San Diego. There&apos;s great Korean food on Convoy Street. Coronado Island is a beautiful place to walk around. Balboa Park is an amazing cultural park to visit. But all of this is out of reach without a car. Most freshmen live on campus their first year and don&apos;t have a car either so it&apos;s difficult to explore without meeting people with a car or taking a long bus ride. Also, I was a bit shocked how little there was to do on campus and around campus why is probably why UCSD students are so studious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Theft Accounts for Most Crimes on Campus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/trips_photos/blog_images/IMG_0114.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Triton&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My freshman year, I had my brand new bike stolen on campus. I had it locked up, but someone was still able to steal it. Apparently in 2014, bicycle theft accounted for $100k of stolen property according to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://triton.news/2016/01/bike-theft-at-ucsd/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;. I also knew people who had their dorms broken into and had their entire suite raided. On the bright side, 95% of crimes on campus are theft related according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucsdguardian.org/2011/01/31/theft-accounts-for-most-crimes-on-campus/&quot;&gt;UCSD Guardian&lt;/a&gt;, so the campus is relatively safe. I&apos;ve actually walked around campus at 3am and it&apos;s pretty much empty. If you do end up getting a bike, I reccommend buying a cheap bike that you don&apos;t mind getting stolen and buying a U Lock like the one linked below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLinksContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B01KD9AQ92&amp;asins=B01KD9AQ92&amp;linkId=15dab09d94b98139a84de1e468f64941&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. The Campus is Huge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/trips_photos/blog_images/Screen%20Shot%202020-07-16%20at%207.08.28%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walking distance&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because there&apos;s multiple colleges and the classes are so spread out from one another, expect to walk a lot. Also, expect all your lecture halls to be in different locations. I sometimes had one lecture at Revelle College and another lecture after at Warren College. According to Google Maps, this will an 0.8 mile walk. In order to deal with these long stretches, I initially had a bike, but learned to longboard after the bike was stolen. Here&apos;s a list of some of the board I used throughout the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateLinksContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B00VKXMV0S&amp;asins=B00VKXMV0S&amp;linkId=e12cb8922e364ed4bbe6809a10b6bddf&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B005NGV9HE&amp;asins=B005NGV9HE&amp;linkId=b990b0742de6fe671dc4897df18b1b4f&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ss&amp;ref=as_ss_li_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B003N38O0Y&amp;asins=B003N38O0Y&amp;linkId=2e7f37e58b3462229f6bb244309102bc&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. The Quality of Dorms is Different for Each College&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/trips_photos/blog_images/IMG_20140928_162011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Village&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to live in three different dorms on campus before moving off campus my 4th year. I lived in Argo Halls in Revelle, Sixth College, and the Village. Amongst these three, I personally liked Sixth College the most. It wasn&apos;t old like Revelle&apos;s dorms and it wasn&apos;t obnoxiously cramped like in the Village. Although, I&apos;m being a bit biased since we got a triplet in The Village. They had reconfigure many of the doubles to triplets so my room was extremely small (that picture from above was literally my corner in the triplet). Also, there were a lot of parties and people blasting music from The Tower at The Village. Another thing to note is that some colleges are strict on underage drinking. My friends and I almost got expelled for having alcohol at Sixth College because there were underage people in the apartment. Interestingly, when we lived in The Village, our suitemates would smoke weed in the apartment everyday and the police didn&apos;t care. Your mileage will range between having a chill RA and whoever is posted onduty that night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Check Out the Farmers Market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there&apos;s a bunch of cafeterias on campus, the cafeteria&apos;s food gets pretty boring really quick. Thankfully, there&apos;s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://ucsandiegobookstore.com/t-farmersmarket.aspx&quot;&gt;Farmers Market&lt;/a&gt; once a week. My favorites include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/torpasta/&quot;&gt;Torpasta&lt;/a&gt; which serves pasta inside of bread and Carranza Citrus Fruit which serves Chamango. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you guys learned something new. Did you attend UCSD as well? Also check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/things-wish-knew-before-going-ucsd-computer-science-major-5ee2265f&quot;&gt;Things I Wish I Knew Before Going to UCSD as a Computer Science Major&lt;/a&gt;. Leave a comment in the comments section below!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Things I Wish I Knew Before Going to UCSD as a Computer Science Major]]></title><description><![CDATA[Computer Engineering is Different from Computer Science ECE 35 At UCSD, we have two different majors related to Computer Science. Computer…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/things-wish-knew-before-going-ucsd-computer-science-major-5ee2265f</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/things-wish-knew-before-going-ucsd-computer-science-major-5ee2265f</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Computer Engineering is Different from Computer Science&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/BLcUBhv&quot; alt=&quot;ECE 35&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At UCSD, we have two different majors related to Computer Science. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ucsd.edu/catalog/curric/CSE-ug.html&quot;&gt;Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; focuses on more of theory and design of algorithms while &lt;a href=&quot;https://cse.ucsd.edu/undergraduate/bs-computer-engineering-0&quot;&gt;Computer Engineering&lt;/a&gt; focuses on a mixture of computer science and Electrical Engineering. I was initially a Computer Engineering major, but I switched to Computer Science my sophmore year because of all the extra Physics and Electrical Engineering classes I had to take. Physics 2B: Electricity and Magnetism and ECE 35: Introduction to Analog Design are a few of the hardest classes I took at UCSD. When I took ECE 35, the class was filled with 200+ students. By the end of the quarter, there was only around 75 students left. I ended up switching to class to Pass/No Pass so it wouldn&apos;t affect my GPA. If you don&apos;t believe me just look at all these &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=ece+35+ucsd+reddit&amp;#x26;oq=ece+35+uc&amp;#x26;aqs=chrome.2.0j69i57j0l2.3048j0j7&amp;#x26;sourceid=chrome&amp;#x26;ie=UTF-8&quot;&gt;Reddit posts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;There are a lot of Undergrad CSE &quot;Weeder Courses&quot;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/YZ6Ttvg&quot; alt=&quot;Doge&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Weeder Courses&quot; are designed to make students reconsider their major or have a high failure rate. At UCSD, many Computer Science majors considered CSE 11, CSE 30, and CSE 20 to be those &quot;Weeder Courses.&quot; Your mileage will vary depending on the Professor as well. You can check &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1vmciJ1CydvfSsFuf_Z0fngOLXdQHuCHEY3UUuAjX-7U/edit#gid=109133524&quot;&gt;this spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; to see the overall distrubtion of grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s a breakdown of the top 10 hardest CSE classes to get an A in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Course&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Teacher&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;% of As&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 131&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rick Ord&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8.1%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 8B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Susan Marx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8.7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 140&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tajana Simunic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 105&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daniele Micciancio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.2%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 132A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Victor Vianu&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.3%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Susan Marx&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.4%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Daniele Micciancio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scott Baden&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.8%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 141&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Steven Swanson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11.0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CSE 132A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alin Deutsch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11.4%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Computer Science isn&apos;t Just About Coding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/CDe0OYV&quot; alt=&quot;Computer Science&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; A lot of people assume (myself included) being a Computer Science major means you&apos;ll code all day, but that&apos;s far from the truth. There&apos;s a lot of theory and math required to understand the whole picture. That&apos;s why you&apos;ll end up taking courses like CSE 105 (Theory of Computation), CSE 101 (Design &amp;#x26; Analysis of Algorithms), and CSE 131 (Compilers). Honestly, when I was taking those courses I always wondered when I would ever use any of this in the real world, but looking back I learned those concepts because now I have a greater  appreciation for Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Easy College Credits For Doing an Internship&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you scored yourself an internship, you can actually get Pass/No Pass credits for it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/eng.ucsd.edu/cseinternshipcourses/&quot;&gt;CSE 197&lt;/a&gt; is a 4 unit course that you take over the summer. When I took it, I had to write weekly blogs about my internship and comment on other people&apos;s posts. It&apos;s an easy way to score some credits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pick the Right College Before Applying&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/VmYmLOs&quot; alt=&quot;Warren&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UCSD is the only UC that has multiple colleges in it. Each college has different GEs and unit requirements. Unfortunately, I didn&apos;t do my homework and randomly applied and ended up Revelle College. Apparently, there&apos;s now a seventh college named Seventh College. When I attended UCSD there was only 6. Some colleges have course requirements that overlap with your major so do your research. If you&apos;re planning on doing Computer Science, try to get into Warren College. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s a list of all the Colleges and their requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://revelle.ucsd.edu/_files/academics/rev-grad-req-nfrs.pdf&quot;&gt;Revelle College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sixth.ucsd.edu/academics/requirements/GERequirements.pdf&quot;&gt;Sixth College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://warren.ucsd.edu/academics/general-education/index.html&quot;&gt;Warren College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://muir.ucsd.edu/academics/degree_reqs.html&quot;&gt;John Muir College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://seventh.ucsd.edu/academics/degree-requirements/index.html&quot;&gt;Seventh College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marshall.ucsd.edu/academics/general-education-requirements.html&quot;&gt;Thurdgood Marshall College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://roosevelt.ucsd.edu/academics/gen-ed/index.html&quot;&gt;Eleanor Roosevelt College&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attend All the Job Fairs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UCSD hosts a bunch of job fairs throughout the year. At these job fairs, a bunch of companies and recruiters come to campus to scout for potential talent. You&apos;ll see a bunch of top tier companies like Google, Facebook, Apple, and Microsoft at these events! The biggest one is usually the one in the Fall since that&apos;s when companies are trying to fill up all their headcount. Plan on getting there early since a bunch of people line up to be the first ones to talk to recruiters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be Prepared to Work Hard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/U5SrrA1&quot; alt=&quot;GPA&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up graduating with a 3.85 GPA, but it wasn&apos;t easy. I spent sleepless nights coding and studying. You&apos;ll also need to learn how manage your time and say no to hanging out. CSE classes aren&apos;t a joke and that&apos;s why Computer Science graduates get paid 6 figure salaries straight out of college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you guys learned something new. Is there something else you guys would like to know? Did you attend UCSD as well? What was your favorite class? Leave a comment in the comments section below!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What is Structured Data and Why do I need it?]]></title><description><![CDATA[What is Structured Data? Ever wondered why some search results on Google have extra bits of information like pricing, ratings, and other…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/what-is-structured-data-and-why-do-i-need-it-a3f06898</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/what-is-structured-data-and-why-do-i-need-it-a3f06898</guid><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;What is Structured Data?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered why some search results on Google have extra bits of information like pricing, ratings, and other pieces of information. This is implemented by adding Structured Data to your website. Let&apos;s look at some sites that have implemented Structured Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/5y0fhUrh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FF7 Search Result&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/fQSwxaZ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Latte Search Result&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/d23ximjh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Philz Search Result&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This information is often picked up by crawlers like Google or Bing by crawling the site and reading metadata in the form of Structured Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is Structured Data? Structured data is a collection of data that is formally organized. This collection of data makes it easier for search engines to crawl and contextualize your content. Let&apos;s look at a real life example of defining an AudioBook. Many AudioBooks have these common traits: published date, author, price, and publication date. Without a formal schema, two people could represent the same AudioBook differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Person 1:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Published Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Author&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$19.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 8, 1949&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;George Orwell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Person 2:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Cost&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Release Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;By&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$19.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;June 8, 1949&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;George Orwell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see that both of these represent the same thing, but are organized in differently. So what can we do to systematically organize them the same way? Well that&apos;s where Structure Data comes in. Structured Data allows developers to organize metadata in the same fashion making it easier for search engines to parse metadata and understand the context of your site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do I Add Structured Data to my Site?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add Structured Data to your site with one of the following formats:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://json-ld.org/&quot;&gt;JSON-LD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/microdata/&quot;&gt;Microdata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDFa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google recommends JSON-LD so we&apos;ll be using that for the rest of the blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add JSON-LD to your site, you&apos;ll add a script tag with &lt;code&gt;type=&quot;application/ld+json&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. Inside the script tag you&apos;ll put a blob of JSON. I snatched the following snippet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonld.com/book/&quot;&gt;jsonld.com&lt;/a&gt; which has great examples of JSON-LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;script type=&quot;application/ld+json&quot;&gt;
{
      &quot;@context&quot;: &quot;https://schema.org&quot;,
      &quot;@type&quot;: &quot;WebPage&quot;,
      &quot;breadcrumb&quot;: &quot;Books &gt; Marketing &gt; JSON&quot;,
      &quot;mainEntity&quot;:{
              &quot;@type&quot;: &quot;Book&quot;,
              &quot;author&quot;: &quot;http://www.example.com/author.html&quot;,
              &quot;bookFormat&quot;: &quot;http://schema.org/EBook&quot;,
              &quot;datePublished&quot;: &quot;2015-05-01&quot;,
              &quot;image&quot;: &quot;coverImage.jpg&quot;,
              &quot;inLanguage&quot;: &quot;English&quot;,
              &quot;isbn&quot;: &quot;00000000&quot;,
              &quot;name&quot;: &quot;The Title of Book&quot;,
              &quot;numberOfPages&quot;: &quot;1234&quot;,
              &quot;offers&quot;: {
                &quot;@type&quot;: &quot;Offer&quot;,
                &quot;availability&quot;: &quot;http://schema.org/InStock&quot;,
                &quot;price&quot;: &quot;9.99&quot;,
                &quot;priceCurrency&quot;: &quot;USD&quot;
              },
              &quot;publisher&quot;: &quot;O&apos;Json Publishing&quot;,
              &quot;aggregateRating&quot;: {
                &quot;@type&quot;: &quot;AggregateRating&quot;,
                &quot;ratingValue&quot;: &quot;4&quot;,
                &quot;reviewCount&quot;: &quot;12&quot;
              }
            }
    }
&amp;#x3C;/script&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/sR6sARNh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;schema.org&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re unsure of which schema to use, you can reference &lt;a href=&quot;https://schema.org/docs/schemas.html&quot;&gt;schema.org&lt;/a&gt; and search for a keyword. For example, if you have a page about Pho recipes, you can type in &quot;recipe&quot; into the search bar and it&apos;ll pull up the schema. I would also recommend looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://jsonld.com/&quot;&gt;jsonld.com&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/data-types/product&quot;&gt;Google Search&apos;s Documentation&lt;/a&gt; for good references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/CRIxx2lh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Google Search&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Validate the Structured Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/yZu9UNIh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Validate Structured Data&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can validate your structured data by running your site through this &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.google.com/structured-data/testing-tool/u/0/&quot;&gt;tool&lt;/a&gt;. It will tell you if your Structured Data is implemented incorrectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Do my Search Results Appear the Same After Implementing Structured Data?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently Google has implemented a subset of items. Some common items include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recipe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critic review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TV &amp;#x26; Movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find a full listing &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/search/docs/guides/search-gallery&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Google&apos;s search engine is a blackbox. Just because you implemented it correctly doesn&apos;t mean it will show up at all since Google has algorithms that determines if the content is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why do I need Structured Data?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Structured Data is not a ranking signal, if correctly implemented, you&apos;ll see an improvement in SEO rankings. Structured data helps search engines understand the content of the page and therefore serve the page for more relevant for search queries. Search results with enriched snippets give more visual appearl which can boost the click through rate. This in turn will lead to more visitors for your site!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you learned something new about Structured Data! What other things have you done to optimize your site? Leave a comment in the comments section below!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Even Software Engineers in Silicon Valley Cannot Afford a Home in the Bay Area]]></title><description><![CDATA[When I first started my career, I had a starting salary of 100k, a 10% targeted bonus, and a 8k worth of stocks a year. When people hear…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/why-even-software-engineers-silicon-valley-cannot-afford-home-bay-area-8037ceb2</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/why-even-software-engineers-silicon-valley-cannot-afford-home-bay-area-8037ceb2</guid><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When I first started my career, I had a starting salary of 100k, a 10% targeted bonus, and a 8k worth of stocks a year. When people hear about this offer, they&apos;re usually shocked to hear I&apos;m still living at home. They usually tell me &quot;you make over 100k why don&apos;t you buy a home already?&quot; I always tell them rent prices are outrageous and homes prices are insane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breakdown of Income&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s first breakdown the monthly income. I generally ignore the bonus because that is paid out once at the end of the year and is heavily taxed on. So this means our monthly income is dependent on salary and stocks. One thing to note is that not all companies pay out stocks on a monthly basis. At my previous company, they paid out stocks on a yearly basis meaning all my expenses are dependent on my salary. Some stocks are also worthless if you&apos;re working at a startup that has not become public yet. So let&apos;s take a look at the worst case scenario where we can only depend on salary. Inputting a salary of $100k into this &lt;a href=&quot;https://smartasset.com/taxes/california-paycheck-calculator&quot;&gt;calculator&lt;/a&gt; shows we take home around $2,600 every two weeks after tax. The after tax is the important part because that&apos;s the money that is used towards groceries, car, and savings. So, let&apos;s assume every month we make $5200 and talk about our monthly expenses as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Breakdown of Expenses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s take a look at some common expenses and see the average costing for each category. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have to eat. There&apos;s no getting around it. This number can change depending on your eating habits and if you cook or eat out, but Numbeo.com’s report finds that the recommended monthly food spending per person in San Francisco is $423.75. Let&apos;s round this down to $400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Car&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the transportation infrastructure in Silicon Valley is bad compared to cities like Tokyo or Shanghai. We don&apos;t have bullet trains or underground subways. Everyone here drives so everyone needs a car. Let&apos;s see how much a loan on a Volkswagen Jetta costs. According to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://cars.usnews.com/cars-trucks/car-loans-and-leasing/car-payment-calculator/2019-volkswagen-jetta-13794&quot;&gt;site&lt;/a&gt;, with a down payment of $5000 on a $17.7k car, you&apos;ll be paying $264 a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/3NZvR1dh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Car loan&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s also take car insurance into account. This will vary based on your age, gender, and car. Running the numbers on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thezebra.com/z/rate-select/&quot;&gt;Zebra.com&lt;/a&gt; against a male in their mid twenties for the Jetta generates an estimated $134 a month. Gas is pretty expensive in the Bay Area as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/JSnHR8Ah.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Car insurance&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually spend $60 a month on gas. So every month you&apos;ll be paying around $467 ($264 + $143 + 60) on the car. Let&apos;s use $470 for the costing breakdown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Loans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many students have to take out a student loan in order to afford their education. In fact, 70% of 2018 graduates had an average of $29,800 in borrowing. Generally, it&apos;s better to pay off the loan as fast as possible, let&apos;s say you pay off the loan in 5 years at a 6% interest rate. This would mean you would owe around $570~ a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rent is by far the most expensive cost  Let&apos;s look at some apartments near Google. The average price for a 1 bedroom apartment starts at $2500 a month. What if I wanted to live farther from work? The rent prices in Campbell (which is about 18 miles away from Mountain View) is a bit cheaper averaging at $2000 a month. Let&apos;s average this around $2250 to have something in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal Care&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all need to get haircuts from time to time. Some people also like to get their nails done or do their eyelashes. Let&apos;s also throw in gym membership costs in this category. I generally spend around $20 on my haircuts. A typical gym membership here costs around $30. Let&apos;s assume we&apos;ll need to spend at least $50 on personal care a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to categorize anything fun related including going out on weekends or that Netflix subscription in this category. Let&apos;s assume every weekend you spend $50 and you have both Netflix and Spotify subscription. That comes out to be $220~ a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After crunching these numbers together, we come up with a total of $3960 (&lt;code&gt;$220 + $50 + $2250 + $570 + $470 + $400 = $3960&lt;/code&gt;). This means we save &lt;code&gt;$1240&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;$5200 - $3960&lt;/code&gt;) a month after expenses for the first 5 years if we have a loan to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/2SIp1HRh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;expense chart&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the loan is paid off, we&apos;ll take in &lt;code&gt;$1810&lt;/code&gt; a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a good idea how much we take home a month, let&apos;s look at some homes in the Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Homes Prices in Bay Area&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A typical home in the Bay Area starts at one million dollars. That&apos;s right. STARTS at one million. Even condos and townhomes are over $500k. Most people don&apos;t buy a home in full. Rather, they take out a loan over 30 years. These loans typically require a down payment of 20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&apos;s see how long it&apos;ll take to save up for a down payment on a $600k condo. Let&apos;s also assume we live in a perfect world where the home prices are fixed since a lot can change from now and 20 years later. I will need to save $120k (&lt;code&gt;20% * 600k&lt;/code&gt;) for the down payment. For the first 5 years, we&apos;ll save up $74,400 (&lt;code&gt;$1240 * 5 * 12&lt;/code&gt;) meaning we only need $45,600 left. Since we don&apos;t need to pay off our students loans, this will take approximately 25 months (&lt;code&gt;$45,600 / $1810&lt;/code&gt;). Ok only 7 years to save up for our every own condo! (This is assuming we are cruising at our job and we never get a raise)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/vqKujPzh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mortgage prices&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we purchase our condo, we&apos;ll need to start paying more expenses. Looking at this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zillow.com/homedetails/1375-Phelps-Ave-APT-2-San-Jose-CA-95117/19609361_zpid/&quot;&gt;$600k condo&lt;/a&gt;, we&apos;ll be paying $2,996 a month on the property. Unfortunately, this is still out of our budget since we only save $1810 a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok what if we 5% raise every year? By the end of year 7, our salary will be at $140k we&apos;ll take in about $7000 a month. Assuming we get a raise every year and home prices aren&apos;t inflating, we&apos;ll be able to buy a home in 7 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Salary&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$100,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$105,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$110,250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$115,762&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$121,550&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$127,628&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$134,009&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$140,710&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/R74M1VYh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Zillow Prices&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that&apos;s not reality. According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doctorhousingbubble.com/san-francisco-real-estate-median-home-price-new-record-sf-bay-area-housing-bubble/&quot;&gt;Dr. House Bubble&lt;/a&gt;, home prices have been steadily rising. Looking at that same condo from above, the home was sold for $365k in 2014, but is now being listed at $600k in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/iVARMswh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Home prices&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the home prices is one of the reasons why many people have been moving out of the Silicon Valley. Homes just feel out of reach for those bringing in over 100k a year. I also think a shift towards remote work could fix some of these issues. As demand for housing decreases, the prices will ideally stabilize as well. Check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/cd2e7615-63de-484d-9572-d1d51a6a8239&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on remote work to learn more about the pros and cons of WFH. What do you guys think? Are you a home owner in the Bay Area? How did you afford your first home? Let&apos;s chat in the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is Working from Home the Future?]]></title><description><![CDATA[2020 has been an eventful year from the wildfires to the Covid-19. One effect of Covid-19 has been the rise of remote work. This has been…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/is-working-from-home-the-future-cd2e7615</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/is-working-from-home-the-future-cd2e7615</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;2020 has been an eventful year from the wildfires to the Covid-19. One effect of Covid-19 has been the rise of remote work. This has been more feasible in 2020 because of the rise of technologies like Zoom and Google Hangouts. As a Software Engineer who has been forced to work from home for 3 months already, I&apos;m starting to see the benefits and the downsides to WFH. Let&apos;s talk about both sides and where I think things will go after the pandemic is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A typical day before the pandemic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a better understanding of the change, let&apos;s see what my daily routine used to be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake up at 7am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leave for work at 8am &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commute for an hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get to work, eat breakfast, and start working at 9am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 hour lunch break around 11:30&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work until 7pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commute home for an hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep at 11pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A typical day during the pandemic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake up at 8:30am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start work at 9am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat lunch while working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work until 6pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep at 12am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest change in my work schedule has been the commute and my lunch break. This has shaved off 3 hours from my schedule to do other things. This schedule doesn&apos;t paint the whole picture of the work environment so lets talk about the pros and cons of remote work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Don&apos;t need to commute&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has shown a longer commutes are linked to unhappiness. Just look at this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/business-insider/study-reveals-commute-time-impacts-job-satisfaction.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; how &quot;adding 20 minutes to your commute makes you as miserable as getting a 19% pay cut.&quot; I agree with this article 100%. I spend 2 hours of my day in Bay Area traffic. It&apos;s honestly infuriating how long it takes to drive 16 miles. Working from home has cut that stressful part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. More time for myself&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have much more time to dedicate to myself since I didn&apos;t need to commute 2 hours everyday. I&apos;ve been picking up old hobbies that I dropped like guitar, making music, exercising, and finishing personal projects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. You can work from anywhere&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of being a Software Engineer is that we only need a laptop and internet to get work done. As a result, Software Engineers have the option to work anywhere they like. Some of my coworkers have even thought about traveling in an RV! Another big benefit of working wherever is the option to live in a cheaper area. Rent in the bay is really expensive. Like really really expensive. Homes cost at least one million and an apartment costs around $3000 a month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Employers don&apos;t need to pay for office space&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is mainly a benefit for your employer. Real estate is expensive and those savings can be put towards other initiatives like bigger bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Meal Prepping&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most companies have a cafe or restaurants nearby. This saves a bunch of time since you don&apos;t need to cook and clean the dishes afterwards. This can get pretty tiring if you do this three times a day for breakfast, lunch, and dinner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Fatiguing to Communicate over Video Chat&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly feel like it&apos;s more tiring to talk to people over video chat especially when there&apos;s 10 other people in the chat. Only one person can talk at a time, you&apos;re never sure if someone is obsessively looking at your video feed, a shady internet can make the experience a total mess. Video chats also lack physical language. We&apos;re required to focus more in order to grasp non-verbal cues like facial expressions and the tone of a voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. No separation between work and home&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s an interesting psychology how the brain associates the location to a behavior. For example, we generally associate parks with fun and relaxation. Most people associate home with rest and work with ... well work. That is why there&apos;s a conflict when we mix the two together. When I first started to work from home, I worked in my bedroom where I play games, make music, and relax. Soon, I felt a sense of dread in my room because I started to associate my room with dreaded work. In order to combat this, I&apos;ve set up a work space in a different room from where I usually spend my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Office equipment is generally nicer than home equipment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The office is generally well furnished with desks, ergo chairs, and big monitors. Not everyone has the luxury or the space for an office in their homes. Not to mention, office equipment can be expensive. A Herman Miller chair costs around $1000 on average while a standing desk usually starts at $500. Let&apos;s not forget the other things in the office like that nice espresso machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve spent a bit on upgrading my home office. I&apos;ll list out some items that have made a big impact on my day to day life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3047Vl7&quot;&gt;Mistel Barocco Ergo Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/38KdXv2&quot;&gt;Logitech MX Ergo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3iT7WRu&quot;&gt;Dell 32 Inch LED Curved QHD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ZVE0eG&quot;&gt;Standing Desk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3iSlLQ2&quot;&gt;Airpods Pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. More distractions at home&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s be honest, we all have some kind of distraction at home. Some people have kids to take care of. Some people have video games sitting there waiting to be played. Some people have noisy roommates who won&apos;t lower the volume on the tv. The work environment is generally pretty quiet and is perfect to keep you focused. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is undebatable that remote work is here to stay. Companies like Facebook, Twitter, Shopify, and Slack all announced initiatives to transition to remote work even after the pandemic is over. I honestly believe the benefits of remote work outweighs the negatives. Not having to commute has made dramatic improvements to my stress levels and my mental health. Not having to pay an outrageous amount for rent is also great. From my experience of working from home for 3 months, there hasn&apos;t been a loss in productivity with the switch to remote. My whole team has been contributing the same amount of work even though we&apos;re not physically together. This convinces me that professions that only require a computer can go full remote. Many of us are already accustomed to messaging one another on the web and using video chats to communicate which makes this transition seamless. I believe the transition to full remote will also fix the housing crisis in hubs like Bay Area, Seattle, and New York. As people leave these cities, the value of the properties inside these cities will decrease. I also imagine we&apos;ll see a reduction in pollution since there will be less people stuck in traffic. We&apos;ll potentially see fewer people owning cars as well. All in all, I believe the transition to remote work will lead to happier and healthier lives due to less commuting, less pollution, and more affordable housing.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Top 3 E-Mount Lens for Shooting Portraits]]></title><description><![CDATA[Back when I first got my Sony Alpha a7ii there weren't that many lens to choose from, but now there's an adundance of lens to use ranging…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/my-top-3-e-mount-lens-for-shooting-portraits-a1ee7bdb</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/my-top-3-e-mount-lens-for-shooting-portraits-a1ee7bdb</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Back when I first got my Sony Alpha a7ii there weren&apos;t that many lens to choose from, but now there&apos;s an adundance of lens to use ranging from Sigma to Zeiss. In this article, we’ll cover my favorite choices of portrait lenses for Sony’s E-mount and some alternative lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What makes a good portrait lens?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people associate a good portrait lens with the ability to create nice and blurred backgrounds while keeping the subject in focus. This is generally achieved with a fast f-stop like f/1.8 (this also depends on whether you&apos;re using a full frame). 85mm is probably the most popular focal length for portraits, but I like to also experiment around with other focal lengths which is why this list contains lens of different focal lengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W26hPw&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 85mm f/1.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Zeiss-Batis-85mm-Lens-Mount/dp/B00WII52ZU/ref=as_li_ss_il?dchild=1&amp;keywords=zeiss+batis+85mm&amp;qid=1594953218&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;psc=1&amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUE0SjVWS0oyWjdEUlcmZW5jcnlwdGVkSWQ9QTA1NTE1NTIzSDJYTURFQTVHTkIwJmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTA2ODYyNDMzSFM2SDhPVUpURE9UJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ==&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=9d0da74f849f2b854710d58bf5f4193d&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B00WII52ZU&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B00WII52ZU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is honestly one of my favorite lens for shooting portraits. I have taken it with me on every trip. The build quality is great and the lens is super fast. This lens also has built-in image stabilization for those hand shot moments. The lens also has an OLED display which displays the distance and depth of field, but I don&apos;t use it very often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095189643_2616167c03_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095998522_818196757e_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095768831_c4d0b8c4b9_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095997912_660134beb8_k.jpg, https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50096045621_d337ad8b58_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;ZeissBatis85Carousel&quot;&gt;&lt;/img-carousel&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Alternative Lens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/38FuQac&quot;&gt;Sony SEL85F18 85mm f/1.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Sony-85mm-1-8-Lens-SEL85F18/dp/B07XF2HBKK/ref=as_li_ss_il?dchild=1&amp;keywords=sony+85mm&amp;qid=1594349642&amp;s=electronics&amp;sr=1-3&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=691fd3652e346adb158fb2a2c20a5004&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B07XF2HBKK&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B07XF2HBKK&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this lens doesn&apos;t have the same build quality as the Zeiss, it has the same focal length and aperture at half the price. This is a great lens if you&apos;re getting started in photography and don&apos;t want to invest over $1000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W53Snh&quot;&gt;Sony FE 70-200mm f/4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/SEL70200G-Sony-70-200-mm-principal/dp/B00I8BICEO/ref=as_li_ss_il?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Sony+FE+70-200mm+f/4+G+OSS+Lens&amp;qid=1594350256&amp;s=electronics&amp;sr=1-3&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=386d5e324344b934df1a2fbdd2b65504&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B00I8BICEO&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B00I8BICEO&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&apos;t like using fixed focal lengths, this lens is for you. It includes Optical Steady Shot which will help you shoot when you&apos;re not using a tripod. The lens has a certain degree of weather resistance as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/38GxFYu&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 18mm f/2.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Zeiss-Batis-85mm-Lens-Mount/dp/B01E8OBQS8/ref=as_li_ss_il?th=1&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=a3c4077d1d533b69e72aa70c8776b6e5&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B01E8OBQS8&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B01E8OBQS8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like the Batis 85mm, this lens is build very well. I generally don&apos;t recommend using wide angel lens for portraits due to perspective distortion. This lens is generally better for full body shots that incorporate the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095981252_c568e8c79c_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095979762_a38d1256e8_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095980962_3d71fb7612_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095980507_93cf03c2a4_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095429403_cbbb807f0a_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;ZeissBatis18Carousel&quot;&gt;
&lt;/img-carousel&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ZUa0jl&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 40mm f/2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Zeiss-Batis-85mm-Lens-Mount/dp/B01E8OBQS8/ref=as_li_ss_il?th=1&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=3da8f1c8bf8f15d50e6583b314b8df69&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B01E8OBQS8&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B01E8OBQS8&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What? Another Zeiss lens? What can I say? I love how well made Zeiss lens are. This lens is quite unique because of the unconventional 40mm focal length. I actually really like it because it sits inbetween 35mm and 50mm. It&apos;s perfect for shooting portraits and street photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-carousel images=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095680616_199a81024a_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095680841_aaaa044b28_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095910507_643f1ca328_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095682031_2da0703bcc_k.jpg,https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50095910862_90c70552dc_k.jpg&quot; id=&quot;ZeissBatis40Carousel&quot;&gt;&lt;/img-carousel&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Alternative Lens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Zf3TH8&quot;&gt;Sony Sonnar 35mm f/2.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Sony-Sonnar-Frame-Prime-Fixed/dp/B00FSB79KU/ref=as_li_ss_il?dchild=1&amp;keywords=Sony+Sonnar+T*+FE+35mm&amp;qid=1594431068&amp;sr=8-2&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=002a719bde40c3aa59a2c3c1f4b0ac43&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B00FSB79KU&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B00FSB79KU&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lens is a much more traditional focal length at 35mm. It&apos;s also cheaper than the Batis at around $800.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Dkj21k&quot;&gt;Sony FE 16-35mm f/2.8 GM &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;AmazonAffiliateImageLink&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Sony-16-35mm-F2-8-Wide-angle-SEL1635GM/dp/B071LHLS11/ref=as_li_ss_il?dchild=1&amp;keywords=e-mount+35mm+g+master&amp;qid=1594351316&amp;s=electronics&amp;sr=1-2&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;linkId=d7490bbeaab2def065b1c8fac183c32d&amp;language=en_US&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B071LHLS11&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&quot; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=onew1ng3dang3-20&amp;language=en_US&amp;l=li3&amp;o=1&amp;a=B071LHLS11&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lens is a much more flexible since you can go from 16 to 35mm making it good for those moments you need a wider field of view and something more traditional like a 35mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to all the photos are in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/150081522@N05/sets/72157715037839271&quot;&gt;album&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which lens do you guys like to use for shooting portraits? Let me know in the comments section below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to all the lens are here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W26hPw&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 85mm f/1.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ZUa0jl&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 40mm f/2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/38GxFYu&quot;&gt;Zeiss Batis 18mm f/2.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2W53Snh&quot;&gt;Sony FE 70-200mm f/4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/38FuQac&quot;&gt;Sony SEL85F18 85mm f/1.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Dkj21k&quot;&gt;Sony FE 16-35mm f/2.8 GM &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3eeWXhu&quot;&gt;Sony SEL35F18 35mm f/1.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to make your website accessible]]></title><description><![CDATA[I believe one of the most important things to consider when designing a website is its accessibility. Designing a website to be universally…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/how-make-your-website-accessible-e77547a0</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/how-make-your-website-accessible-e77547a0</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I believe one of the most important things to consider when designing a website is its accessibility. Designing a website to be universally accessible allows products to be more widely used. In fact, Google&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.google/&quot;&gt;mission&lt;/a&gt; &quot;is to organize the world&apos;s information and make it universally accessible and useful.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is accessibility?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people may have special needs or have impairments that make it difficult to use some products. When you design your site with accessibility in mind, it will allow all kinds of users to use your product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some common impairments can include&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hearing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motor Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photosensitive Seizures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with these kinds of impairments can enable special settings to help them use their devices more easily. I like to use VoiceOver when testing which is used by those with visual impairments. When VoiceOver is enabled, the device will read out text when an item is tapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/wvqC6BQ&quot; alt=&quot;Voice Over&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How can I check how accessible my site is?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome makes it super easy to run an audit of your site. In the developer tools, there is a lighthouse tab which will let you run an audit of the current page you&apos;re on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/Q1B2Qv8&quot; alt=&quot;Lighthouse&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will list all the elements that need to be correct. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/aQHTvoU&quot; alt=&quot;Lighthouse Report&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that only a subset of accessibility issues can be automatically detected so manual testing is also encouraged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5 Simple Ways to Make Your Site More Accessible&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Add Alt Text to Every Image&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alt text is what screen readers read out when an image is tapped. This will give the user some context as to what the image is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/eirEsqb&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/d8dzF1V&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of my 10 year old cat&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Only One H1 tag on the Page&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a common mistake a lot of websites have. I see a lot of people using more than one &lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;h1&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag on the page. Reserve the &lt;code&gt;h1&lt;/code&gt; for for titles of or main topic of the page. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://codex.wordpress.org/Designing_Headings&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; explains some of the common usecases for h1, h2, and h3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Use semantic html tags&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another common mistake is using the wrong html tag in the wrong place. Let&apos;s look at the following example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;button onclick=&quot;navigateToHome()&quot;&gt;Home&amp;#x3C;/button&gt;
&amp;#x3C;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Home&amp;#x3C;/a&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While these two may look and act same, this won&apos;t behave the same when using a screen reader. The screen readers will actually announce the type of element you&apos;re touching. So when you&apos;re touching a button, the screen reader will announce &quot;Home Button.&quot; Similarily, the screen reader will announce &quot;Home Link&quot; when you tap on the anchor tag. (What the voice reader announces will vary depending on the device and OS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Preserve Functionality for Users Using a Keyboard&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some users do not use a mouse to navigate through your page. One way to test if all the elements on the page are reachable by a keyboard is to press the &lt;code&gt;tab&lt;/code&gt; key. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/p8WicV8&quot; alt=&quot;Navigation by keyboard&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you might want to control the sequence in which elements should be focused. This can be achieved by &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Global_attributes/tabindex&quot;&gt;tabindex&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;code&gt;tabindex=-1&lt;/code&gt; means the element cannot be reached by keyboard. A positive index means the element should be focusable in sequential keyboard navigation, with its order defined by the value of the number. For example, &lt;code&gt;tabindex=1&lt;/code&gt; will be focused on before &lt;code&gt;tabindex=2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Use Aria Labels When Appropriate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are times where you properly use semantic html tags, but you want assistive technologies to read something different. For example, a lot of websites use an &quot;x&quot; as a close button. An easy way is to use the &quot;x&quot; key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;button onclick=&quot;close()&quot;&gt;X&amp;#x3C;/button&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with this is that the screenreader will announce &quot;X Button&quot; which would be confusing for those who can&apos;t see the page. To get around this, you can use an &lt;code&gt;aria-label&lt;/code&gt; which is basically like an img&apos;s alt text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;button aria-label=&quot;Close&quot; onclick=&quot;close()&quot;&gt;X&amp;#x3C;/button&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the follow up example, the screen reader will announce the button as &quot;Close Button&quot; which is much more useful than &quot;X Button.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you now have a better understanding why we should design for accessibility. These key takeaways will both make your site more usable for more people, but it will also help search engines understand your site better. How accessible are your products? What changes have you made to improve the accessibility of your product? Share your thoughts and experience in the comments section below.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Leica Q2 First Impressions]]></title><description><![CDATA[Unboxing The Leica Q2 is my third camera and it's by far my favorite so far. The packaging is super ecofriendly; although its a bit cheap…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/leica-q2-first-impressions-a0297887</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/leica-q2-first-impressions-a0297887</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Unboxing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2NZx1fm&quot;&gt;Leica Q2&lt;/a&gt; is my third camera and it&apos;s by far my favorite so far. The packaging is super ecofriendly; although its a bit cheap considering the camera costs $5000. The drawer design is pretty nice, but the whole experience doesn&apos;t scream &apos;luxary&apos;. The packaging doesn&apos;t come with too much either. Other than the camera, you also get a leather strap, a lens cap, a lens hood, a charger, and a single battery. At the end of the day, I think it&apos;s great that the box packaging makes it super easy to recycle and camera is what&apos;s most important anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/1kpaOaLl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Q2 Box&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/xqUyAzml.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Q2 Box&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/m28HDwD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Q2 Box&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Specs &amp;#x26; Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specs&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Max resolution&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8368 x 5584&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Effective pixels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;47 megapixels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sensor size&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Full frame (36 x 24 mm)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sensor type&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CMOS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ISO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50-50000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Focal length&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;28 mm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Max aperture&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;F1.7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shutter speed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1/40000 sec - 2 min&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Weight with battery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;734 g (1.62 lb / 25.89 oz)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dimensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;130 x 80 x 92 mm (5.12 x 3.15 x 3.62&quot;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Other key features&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;f/1.7 Summilux lens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.68MP OLED EVF with 0.76x magnification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4K video capture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wi-Fi and Bluetooth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Build Quality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build quality is no joke. The body is made of magnesium-alloy making the camera weigh 718g, but it still feels light enough to carry it around. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2NZx1fm&quot;&gt;Leica Q2&lt;/a&gt; has an IP52 rating which means some dust, sand, and light rain won&apos;t stop it from working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day to day handling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the camera looks amazing in pictures, the camera can be a bit uncomfortable to hold since it doesn&apos;t come with a grip. You can optionally buy a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OeaYlf&quot;&gt;Thumb Grip&lt;/a&gt; and/or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2O3t5Ky&quot;&gt;Hand Grip&lt;/a&gt; to make the ergonomics a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For better or worse, there aren&apos;t that many buttons on the Leica Q2. Personally, I&apos;m a fan of minimalistic design so this doesn&apos;t bother me too much, but some people may miss having a bunch of custom function keys or dedicated video recording buttons if you&apos;re coming from other cameras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera comes with a touchscreen, but it doesn&apos;t work when you&apos;re in the settings. I never use the touchscreens on my cameras, but it&apos;s there if you need it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that you&apos;ll probably notice from day to day shooting is that the images are massive. A single RAW file is almost 85MB and a JPG file is almost 20MB. This is something to keep in mind if you don&apos;t have a high speed/high capacity memory card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Photos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly really like how the photos look out of the camera. This has not been the case with other cameras I&apos;ve used like the Sony Alpha a7II, which always needed a bit of tweaking to look nice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: All of these photos were taken before the COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50085296256_d888a5021f_o.jpg?width=8368&amp;#x26;height=5584&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Q2 Sample&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/2jiSeCC&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50085302286_6f3cfb0323_o.jpg?width=8368&amp;#x26;height=5584&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Q2 Sample&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/2jiShTv&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50085307211_2ab9aed5c0_o.jpg?width=8368&amp;#x26;height=5584&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Q2 Sample&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/2jiSgqA&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50084715193_fd37fd6b4f_o.jpg?width=8368&amp;#x26;height=5584&quot; alt=&quot;Leica Q2 Sample&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/2jiPfUi&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accessories&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There aren&apos;t many accessories you can buy for the Leica Q2, but I did come across a couple of items to make the experience better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2BJNjpZ&quot;&gt;Vi Vante Sheetline Black Rope Luxury Camera Neck Strap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m honestly not a big fan of the leather strap the camera comes with, so I replaced it with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3f7kEtk&quot;&gt;Leica T-System case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bag is nice and compact. Even though it&apos;s meant for the T-System, it fits the Leica Q2 perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/iuVMBIEl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leica T-System case&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/CejOLBHl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leica T-System case&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I&apos;m super happy with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2NZx1fm&quot;&gt;Leica Q2&lt;/a&gt;. I&apos;m not a professional photographer by any means, but I firmly believe the Leica Q2 is a great camera to take on a trip. The small compact form factor paired with the amazing Summilux makes it a general camera.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why I'm using Gatsby to create my blog site]]></title><description><![CDATA[Why Use Gatsby for My Blog? There are so many options for creating your blog in 2020 ranging from making it yourself to using something like…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/why-im-using-gatsby-to-create-my-blog-site-ea5d243a</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/why-im-using-gatsby-to-create-my-blog-site-ea5d243a</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Why Use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; for My Blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many options for creating your blog in 2020 ranging from making it yourself to using something like Wordpress. With all these options, why did I pick Gatsby? The answer is simple - speed. Gatsby is a static-site generator which means the entire site is generate at build time rather than dynamically. Solutions like Wordpress are database driven, so when a person visits a site generated by Wordpress, the server will grab all the necessary data from a Database in order to generate the page. Gatsby on the other hand already generated the page before the user has visited the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gatsby Uses Modern Web Tech&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gatsby uses React, Webpack, and other modern technologies out of the box. You can add plugins to support SASS, Typescript, and other modern frameworks/libraries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve tried out other Static Site generators in the past like Jekyll and with some hacking around, you can get React to work with it, but Gatsby supports React out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gatsby is Fast and No server costs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; to host my site. It&apos;s absolutely free and deployment literally takes minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the site is generated at build time, Gatsby generated pages are super fast and makes it super easy to configure as a PWA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/oxwp4Y5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Speed&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plethora of plugins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-plugin-react-helmet/?=&quot;&gt;20000+ plugins&lt;/a&gt; that you can install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorites include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-plugin-sitemap/?=&quot;&gt;gatsby-plugin-sitemap&lt;/a&gt;: This will generate a sitemap.xml for you automatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-plugin-offline/?=gatsby-plugin-offline&quot;&gt;gatsby-plugin-offline&lt;/a&gt;: This will allow visited sites to work offline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-source-filesystem/?=gatsby-source-filesystem&quot;&gt;gatsby-source-filesystem&lt;/a&gt;: I&apos;m using this to read a bunch of markdown to generate all my blog posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/packages/gatsby-plugin-manifest/?=gatsby-plugin-manifest&quot;&gt;gatsby-plugin-manifest&lt;/a&gt;: This will turn your site into a PWA with minimal effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Gatsby &amp;#x26; GraphQL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You access your data using GraphQL which makes it super simple to grab the data you need. This makes it super easy to create all sorts of pages such as your typical &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/5165ea28-a7b5-4947-a9f8-5f0e199b1fb9&quot;&gt;Blog Post&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techwaifu.com/tech&quot;&gt;Paginated Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;const blogListQuery = graphql`
  query blogListQuery($skip: Int!, $limit: Int!) {
    allMarkdownRemark(
      sort: {
          order: DESC, fields: [frontmatter___date],
      }
      limit: $limit
      skip: $skip
    ) {
      pageInfo {
        hasNextPage
        currentPage
        hasPreviousPage
      }
      edges {
        node {
          id
          excerpt
          frontmatter {
            slug
            title
            date(formatString: &quot;MMMM D, YYYY&quot;)
            cover_photo
          }
        }
      }
    }
  }
`
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Get Unlimited Original Quality on Google Photos]]></title><description><![CDATA[Google Photos is an excellent product that allows users to upload all of their photos to the cloud for free which makes it super easy to…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/how-get-unlimited-original-quality-google-photos-e0a71ee5</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/how-get-unlimited-original-quality-google-photos-e0a71ee5</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Google Photos is an excellent product that allows users to upload all of their photos to the cloud for free which makes it super easy to share photos and revisit memories. Many of us might not know that Google is actually compressing our photos when they get uploaded. This free tier is called &quot;High quality&quot;, but you can actually upload all your photos in &quot;Original quality&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How does High Quality compare with Original Quality?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a good idea of what High Quality looks like compared to Original Quality, I&apos;ve uploaded the same photo in both formats. One noticable difference is the size of the images. The High Quality file is 651 KB while Original Quality is 2.3MB. That&apos;s almost a 4x size reduction! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-compare leftImage=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50076460491_ba05a13a65_o.jpg&quot; rightImage=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50076460561_d1f9c7f271_o.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/img-compare&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most of your photos taken on a smartphone, this compression might not matter that much, but what about high res photos taken from a DSLR? The Original Quality is on the left and the High Quality is on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img-compare leftImage=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50076563296_26213e35dd_o.jpg&quot; rightImage=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50076563561_c3e359998f_o.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/img-compare&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out the Original Image &lt;a href=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50076563296_26213e35dd_o.jpg&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the High Quality Image &lt;a href=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50076563561_c3e359998f_o.jpg&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;So how do I get unlimited storage?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pixel owners have unlimited free storage at Original quality; however, only the Pixel 1 has this promotion forever. Check this &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/googleone/answer/6220791?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&amp;#x26;oco=1#storage&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; for your device&apos;s compatibility. If you own a Pixel 2 or Pixel 3, the images you uploaded will remain Original quality even after the Original quality offer period. Unfortunately, Google stopped offering this service with the Pixel 4. :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One cool trick is to transfer photos taken from other devices to a Pixel device and those photos will be uploaded at Original quality. I&apos;ve uploaded over 1TB worth of photos and videos taken on my DSLR cameras and transferred them over to my Pixel to upload!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the promotion only lasts forever for Pixel 1 devices I would recommend purchasing one to take advantage of the free Cloud storage. Pixel 1 devices are pretty cheap to buy used these days. You can find a bunch of used Pixel 1s for less than $100 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2NY1ZnQ&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2NY1ZnQ&quot;&gt;Pixel 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3gtdnEE&quot;&gt;Pixel 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Avk8X3&quot;&gt;Pixel 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Coding on an iPad]]></title><description><![CDATA[The iPad has come a long way since its initial debut in 2010. Nowadays there's almost an app for everything including some nice programming…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/coding-on-an-ipad-190ccc96</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/coding-on-an-ipad-190ccc96</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The iPad has come a long way since its initial debut in 2010. Nowadays there&apos;s almost an app for everything including some nice programming apps. I&apos;ll be going over some of my favorite apps that I use for coding on my iPad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing python apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/kosajyUl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Juno&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/app/id1462586500&quot;&gt;Juno&lt;/a&gt; is a complete Jupyter development environment for your iOS device. It&apos;s super powerful and can leverage NumPy, Matplotlib, and Pandas out of the box. It&apos;s also super flexible since you can install Python packages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/eJPPMshl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pythonista&quot;&gt;
An alternative IDE for coding in Python is &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pythonista-3/id1085978097&quot;&gt;Pythonista&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making a Web app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/cif2rval.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;play.js&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/play-js-javascript-ide/id1423330822&quot;&gt;play.js&lt;/a&gt; is by far the BEST Javascript IDE on IOS if you&apos;re a fan of using React.js or Vue.js. The best part is you can even install npm packages on this IDE! It sets up a Node.JS server out of the box as well, so you can also create a backend service to go along with the frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making a React Native app&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/SjjrSkHl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;React Native app on iOS&quot;&gt;
Guess what? &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/play-js-javascript-ide/id1423330822&quot;&gt;play.js&lt;/a&gt; even supports creating React Native apps! I haven&apos;t delve too deep with making a React Native app via play.js, but it&apos;s nice to have this option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SSH into a machine in the cloud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/hWwiASvl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Blink&quot;&gt;
Sometimes your device isn&apos;t powerful enough and you need a bigger and badder machine in the cloud. That&apos;s where &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/app/id1156707581&quot;&gt;Blink&lt;/a&gt; comes in. I use Blink to SSH into my Mac Mini which is my main development machine. This will require a bit of setup on your personal machine to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macworld.co.uk/how-to/mac-software/how-open-specific-ports-in-os-x-1010-firewall-3616405&quot;&gt;open up a port&lt;/a&gt; to SSH and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macinstruct.com/node/550&quot;&gt;configure a static IP address&lt;/a&gt;. If you don&apos;t own a machine to SSH into, you can use some Cloud offerings like &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/compute/new-using-amazon-ec2-instance-connect-for-ssh-access-to-your-ec2-instances/&quot;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other useful tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dash-offline-api-docs/id1239167694&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;/a&gt; is an API documentation browser which is super useful when you&apos;re coding without internet. Unfortunately, the developer has stopped further development of this app, but it&apos;s still useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2VKMMe7&quot;&gt;Smart Keyboard Folio&lt;/a&gt; for typing on the iPad, but I never enjoyed it since the keys were super mushy and didn&apos;t feel like a true laptop replacement. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3iwuh6X&quot;&gt;iPad Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; has completely changed my perspective of typing on an iPad. Alternatively, if the iPad Magic Keyboard is too expensive, I would recommend buying &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2C3QOHA&quot;&gt;Apple Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt; which is only $81 as today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2VKMMe7&quot;&gt;Smart Keyboard Folio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3iwuh6X&quot;&gt;iPad Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2C3QOHA&quot;&gt;Apple Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dash-offline-api-docs/id1239167694&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/app/id1156707581&quot;&gt;Blink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/play-js-javascript-ide/id1423330822&quot;&gt;play.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pythonista-3/id1085978097&quot;&gt;Pythonista&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/app/id1462586500&quot;&gt;Juno&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to host a website for free]]></title><description><![CDATA[I recently started my own blog site. It was super simple to make and cost me almost nothing. I’ll be teaching you guys step by step how you…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/how-to-host-a-website-for-free-5165ea28</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/how-to-host-a-website-for-free-5165ea28</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I recently started my own blog site. It was super simple to make and cost me almost nothing. I’ll be teaching you guys step by step how you can set up your own website as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set up a Github pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll need a basic level of programming in order to do this, but don’t worry, I’ll guide you through it.
First create an account on Github if you don’t have one already. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After setting up your account, follow the steps listed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a public repository. The repo must have the same name as your github username.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/67OvRxDh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Repo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;https://desktop.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Desktop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will help you pushing your code to the repository. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &quot;Set up in Desktop&quot; button. When the GitHub desktop app opens, save the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an index.html inside that cloned folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a sample index.html file you can copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#x3C;!doctype html&gt;

&amp;#x3C;html lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&amp;#x3C;head&gt;
  &amp;#x3C;meta charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;
  &amp;#x3C;title&gt;Mai’s site&amp;#x3C;/title&gt;
  &amp;#x3C;meta name=&quot;description&quot; content=&quot;Your first website&quot;&gt;
  &amp;#x3C;meta name=&quot;author&quot; content=&quot;Mai&quot;&gt;
&amp;#x3C;/head&gt;

&amp;#x3C;body&gt;
    &amp;#x3C;h1&gt;Hello World&amp;#x3C;/h1&gt;
&amp;#x3C;/body&gt;
&amp;#x3C;/html&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit &amp;#x26; publish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the repository, commit your changes, and press the publish button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;6&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View your website!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will take a couple of seconds before your site is live. You can find it at &lt;a href=&quot;https://username.github.io&quot;&gt;https://username.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. For example, you can find mine at &lt;a href=&quot;https://xonew1ng3dang3lx.github.io/&quot;&gt;xonew1ng3dang3lx.github.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acquiring your very own domain name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This step is totally optional if you’re okay with using the URL provided by Github Pages. However, that URL is not exactly the most memorable URL, but thankfully you can purchase your own domain name to change it. I purchased mine for $1 at &lt;a href=&quot;http://godaddy.com&quot;&gt;Go Daddy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide what domain name you would like to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is honestly the hardest part. Some domains can range from $1 to thousands depending on the popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure the DNS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we&apos;ll need to point your newly acquired domain name to your site hosted on Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Type &quot;A&quot; row update the IP address to: 185.199.108.153&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the CNAME row with Name &quot;www&quot; input your gh-pages website (username.github.io)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the bottom click the &quot;ADD&quot; button and make 3 more Type &quot;A&quot; rows with the IP addresses of: 185.199.109.153, 185.199.110.153, 185.199.111.153 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will look something like this afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/U7zLlq4h.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DNS&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push a CNAME file in your repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/GhEGImIh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CNAME&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable HTTPS in your Github settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&apos;t enable HTTPS, Chrome may consider your site as insecure. In order to make it secure, head over to your repository&apos;s settings and toggle on &quot;Enforce HTTPS&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgur.com/LsRFqSnh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;HTTPS&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Free Image Hosting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can either check in your images directly to your Github repository or you can host them somewhere else. I’m using Imgur since they won’t delete any uploaded images if they’re uploaded from an account. Check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://thomas.vanhoutte.be/miniblog/imgur-thumbnail-trick/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to customize the size of the images as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pink & White Minimalist Gaming Setup]]></title><description><![CDATA[Whether you want to start your twitch streaming career or you want to build a nice set up for your gaming sessions, there are many options…]]></description><link>https://techwaifu.com/pink-white-minimalist-gaming-setup-48418c33</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://techwaifu.com/pink-white-minimalist-gaming-setup-48418c33</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Whether you want to start your twitch streaming career or you want to build a nice set up for your gaming sessions, there are many options for gamers of every level. Most PC gaming setups have a dark edgy ‘macho’ vibe, so if you&apos;re the opposite and want a setup that matches your soft and girly aesthetics, below are seven things I&apos;d recommend to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/38pC6H2&quot;&gt;Quartz Razer Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking for a gaming keyboard, you’ll want to keep in mind what switches it uses. The Quartz Razer keyboard is a mechanical keyboard, so the keys are louder and more robust. Just a personal preference, but I enjoy when my keys feel more clicky and responsive. Another positive aspect is that the keys are raised a bit up so it’s easy to clean. You can  customize the lighting for each key to your liking and it also includes a removable wrist rest that makes typing comfortable. I’ve played long hours on Overwatch and Monster hunter on this keyboard and I have no complaints. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ZEVNXi&quot;&gt;Razer Headphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These headphones are definitely a 10/10 in my book. What’s great about these headphones is that they are lightweight and over-the-ears. They reduce background and ambient noises and they still remain comfortable after wearing them for a long time. It comes with a built-in mic that my friends have no issue in hearing me talk. You can also add the neko ears and feel cute even after a streak of losing matches. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3dZ0q3u&quot;&gt;Razer Basilisk mouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely love this mouse! This is the first gamer mouse I&apos;ve used and I was surprised at how smooth it was. I have small hands but I have a good grip of the mouse so it always feels comfortable. I’ll be honest and say the pink color was the main reason why I bought it but I’m happy the quality has been amazing. Not only does it feel more luxurious than cheap, it is also fully customizable from DPI settings and lets me match the glow of my keyboard making my setup 100x slicker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31K26f8&quot;&gt;Razer Quartz Headset Stand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No headset is complete without its stand. The first week Razer had launched that Razer Quartz stand, I was devastated at how it sold out so quickly. This stand is definitely one of the pieces that gives your setup a nice touch. It has multiple 3x Port USB Hub which makes it extremely convenient to  plug in your essentials usb cables.  You can also customize the LED color to your personal taste. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Samsung 351 Series S32F351&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big white monitor to compliment your gaming needs. It is lightweight,  good build quality, and worth it for a simple setup. Although the screen resolution is not the greatest, the games still look decent and have high contrast. You can easily adjust the brightness and contrast of your screen. Since this monitor is no longer on the market, I would recommend to friends the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2CarEa8&quot;&gt;Samsung 32 inch CF391 Curved Monitor&lt;/a&gt; which is also a good monitor for a new simple PC build. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2NWByPq&quot;&gt;Pioneer Pro DJ DM-40-W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These speakers have not let me down. For great quality, this is an excellent cheaper alternative to studio speakers. I recommend using them as computer desktop speakers. They are amazing while you game or work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;7. LINNMON / ALEX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, no gaming setup is complete without a white desk. You’re welcome to purchase any desk of your choice. For me, I like my desk to be as simple as possible. This desk from IKEA does a good job achieving the minimalist look with a good spacious size to still be useful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2D1uXRx&quot;&gt;Razer DVA headset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2NWByPq&quot;&gt;Pioneer Pro DJ DM-40-W&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31K26f8&quot;&gt;Razer Quartz Headset Stand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3dZ0q3u&quot;&gt;Razer Basilisk mouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2ZEVNXi&quot;&gt;Razer Headphones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2CarEa8&quot;&gt;Samsung 32 inch CF391 Curved Monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>